<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nolan on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/nolan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nolan on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 15:18:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/nolan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Insomnia</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/insomnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 15:18:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/insomnia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have seen both Insomnias - first the one by Nolan and then the one by Skjoldbjærg.&#xA;I wanted to record something on this so Nolan goes first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First I recognized some Twin Peaks atmosphere to it.&#xA;Then also Nolan very explicitly plays with one straightforward idea and you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it.&#xA;This adds entertainment value all over the movie however slow it seems to be.&#xA;Interestingly it makes some scenes way more memorable because you have more structure to them.&#xA;Then surely given unusual state of affairs of roles Al Pacino offers another entertaining piece of the picture.&#xA;Also I think innate visual fabric of the movie may suggest some further ideas but it is as if some frame or composition is not there to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memento</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 05:17:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I ended-up watching some movies recently.&#xA;One of them ended-up being Memento.&#xA;Movies were good but I had no idea for a post until yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is that things that are not expressed may end-up being non-existing in the first place.&#xA;This may not be an idea behind the movie but this is the idea behind the post in its way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;movie&#34;&gt;Movie&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie is an interesting patchwork of scenes that go in reverse chronological order.&#xA;Each has its own references mostly in regard to questions of memory and communication.&#xA;I found topic of drugs abuse and isolation being represented too but more indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
