<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mind on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/mind/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mind on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:54:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/mind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 09:54:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-moon/</guid>
      <description>In the morning I looked at the the Moon movement against the horizon, spire and the clear sky. I assume stars could be similarly useful background too.
Movement perception and image perception are somewhat different systems as scientific evidence established and that idea is already entertaining by itself. But the subjective experience has it&amp;rsquo;s own weight.
And if you are me then surely you would have five interesting hypotheses about how your movement vector could have been biased and start writing about it until evidence shows sufficiently that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:28:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/horizon/</guid>
      <description>Checked OED and Britannica as I have them. Also asked ChatGPT a bit but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t useful in this regard. One definition of horizon is a boundary line at which the earth and sky appear to meet. Other connotations are: boundary, limit, stage/level.
Add the notion of planning/time horizon and the difference it makes to how mind processes things. And this makes things interesting. This has to be a profound idea or image at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wing/Mind</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:49:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/wing/</guid>
      <description>Overall I avoided flying before. So flying to Belgrade was a mixed experience for me.
I have this anchored to the planes wing.
When I looked at the wing it was like more technical mind switches-on and starts modelling reality near me. And that was not very comfortable mode.
Looking at the clouds and the Black Sea likely switched-on more relaxed and more aesthetical mind and the observed reality was having less of me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditating again</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 10:07:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</guid>
      <description>Background facts I have not practiced consistently. And I consumed alot of content about it at some point and have forgotten most of it.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;m getting to know meditation again. With the first breathes you get to observe/experience Tanha directly. Also the alternative &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; is available. This is something new for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
