<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 10:15:05 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dream Flies</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/dream-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 10:15:05 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/dream-flies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I got a random dream some days ago.&#xA;In a dream I smoked (which IRL I didn&amp;rsquo;t do for a number of years).&#xA;Then a bunch of flies showed up and some got stuck to my hand and one even got into my nose forcing me to forcefully breath-out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like how my brain is smart and has intervened in this direct manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shorts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 17:58:46 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shorts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are alot of fools&amp;hellip; More than they think there are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sect of Blindness</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sect-of-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 15:17:44 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sect-of-blindness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I heave read about some strange practices that some marginal groups or individuals praticed.&#xA;So there was something like trying to force oneself into seeing non-existing things and not seeing things that are there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It looks like these days there are adpets at every corner.&#xA;And they have acheived highest levels of trance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I assume levels of subversion with the advent of mass media are so high.&#xA;That they don&amp;rsquo;t need to pratice anything to get that state.&#xA;Distraction should be an important component too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Code Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 17:31:40 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I decided to put some thoughts about my coding here.&#xA;There are three of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;copy-pasting&#34;&gt;Copy-pasting&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is one of my time wasters. I have this expectation that copy-pasted block should just work.&#xA;But then there are little details that I miss that require a debugging session later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copy pasting by itself is not that evil.&#xA;It can be avoided by additional abstractions.&#xA;But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit to any random abstraction either.&#xA;So it is okay to KISS stuff with copy pasting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Till You Make It</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:46:25 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I noticed that I feel unusually proud of myself.&#xA;I thought that there has to be a reason for that.&#xA;And indeed I found couple of them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I thought that feeling of pride is not really concious in it&amp;rsquo;s source.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then I thought about artificial sources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given say body positivity.&#xA;When say fat people are told to feel or pretend to be proud of themselves.&#xA;This is ambiguous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Dentist Experience</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:22:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-time&#34;&gt;This time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I was about to visit a dentist today.&#xA;It was my last visit in this &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;And I needed to fix a wisdom tooth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And I randomly recollected that at some point in the past when a dentist was injecting anesthesia&#xA;it felt like they are injecting the needle right into the bone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And since this was my last visit I felt like experimentating and not injecting anything this time.&#xA;But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I will really decide to not use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
