<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bunuel on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/bunuel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bunuel on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 13:02:48 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/bunuel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simon of Desert</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 13:02:48 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</guid>
      <description>I watched alot of stuff in 2021 that I&amp;rsquo;d like to write something about just to see how it goes. But there should be a starting point somewhere and the most recent movie is the subject of the post.&#xA;The movie is short so the post should follow the shape of the movie.&#xA;What I have seen is lots of patches with with some light humour everywhere in between. Patches are different and that may be confusing because it looks like there are serious topics interwoven.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viridiana</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 20:10:41 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</guid>
      <description>I did not expect this from a black and white movie somehow but it always finds a way to astonish you.&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to add here because it is plain yet very effective. I have strong impression that there is no puzzle that I&amp;rsquo;m so used to like. But the experience by itself does not ask for explanation. It is just that odd and in a way immutable. This way of looking at it seems new to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Charme Discret De La Bourgeoisie</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 22:05:28 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</guid>
      <description>I saw it before and it left vaguely positive memory.&#xA;Overall the picture is light, it is composed from losely tied scenes with some level of humour and absurdity.&#xA;I have enjoyed pleasant dialogues and the level of etiquette.&#xA;Also humour is low key but can be very fun. Original audio track is a must.&#xA;NOTE: some spoilers ahead&#xA;The movie should be rewatcheable because of how subtle the humour is.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
