<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:20 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; Hear me today discursing in the house of Quadratus.
&amp;ndash; Why should I hear you? Do you wish to show me that you put words together cleverly? You put them together man. And what good will it do you?
 So I have completed listening an audiobook of teachings of Epictetus. The audiobook is performed by Hayward Morse.
The content is both very sober, straightforward and logical. And also entertaining and with a lot of humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 18:00:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>I knew about the guy previously but I was avoiding getting into his stuff at all. But this time I decided to look into his content.
First I got into some debate youtube videos of him. And it was ok.
So I decided to look into his audiobook.
I found the first part quite informative for me:
 I really like biological facts about how things work Christianity as a big sacrafice was new information for me I also enjoyed different literary excerpts (Dostoevsky and others)  But then after 50% the real fun starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Lies</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</guid>
      <description>While reading Marxism by T. Sowell I cought myself on thoughts that the stuff is not as ugly as what is claimed to be applications of it. The stuff even felt attractive in theory.
So I quickly visited one site to see what ideas are there these days.
What I found is some pool of mud filled with red-herrings and repeated talking points. It didn&amp;rsquo;t look that the writers are entirely dumb but that they are a bit psychotic and very ideological and partisan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D and D</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 20:04:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of things that I noticed while reading &amp;ldquo;Discrimination and Disparities&amp;rdquo; by T. Sowell.
Obviously the authour is a very logical and factual no BS guy.
The book is full of tricks politicans use and facts they tend to hide.
I noticed this disambiguation of the term &amp;ldquo;discrimination&amp;rdquo; by the author:
 evidence based discrimination (1A): based on knowledge of traits and behavior of a given individual evidence based discrimination (1B): based on statistics on group behavior, traits arbitrary discrimination (2): arbitrary/irrational  This is how I understood this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tar Pit</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:27:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write short summary and some ideas after reading &amp;ldquo;Out of the Tar Pit&amp;rdquo;.
Summary It looks like a theoretical high level paper about comlexity in large codebases.
The main point can be statend in the form: eliminate stuff/separate certain parts of the system to reduce power/ability to introduce accedintal complexity.
What is being separated: essential state, essential logic, control.
Also proposed ways to implement these parts: - state - relaitons - logic - pure functions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das Right</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 09:39:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; is the most prominent example of language abuse for politics sake.
 It is short and not some yet another pseudo scientific &amp;ldquo;-ism&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;-fobia&amp;rdquo;. So it looks more natural on the outset; It has &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; in it :) You can create new &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; every day by adding different perfixes; You can use it to extract something from somebody; Since it is vague term it can have broad uses especially when it comes to general public; It also informs users on how to act/behave when demanding something from others: righteously;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Code Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 17:31:40 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>So I decided to put some thoughts about my coding here. There are three of them.
Copy-pasting This is one of my time wasters. I have this expectation that copy-pasted block should just work. But then there are little details that I miss that require a debugging session later.
Copy pasting by itself is not that evil. It can be avoided by additional abstractions. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit to any random abstraction either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Till You Make It</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:46:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</guid>
      <description>Today I noticed that I feel unusually proud of myself. I thought that there has to be a reason for that. And indeed I found couple of them.
Then I thought that feeling of pride is not really concious in it&amp;rsquo;s source.
And then I thought about artificial sources.
Given say body positivity. When say fat people are told to feel or pretend to be proud of themselves. This is ambiguous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Dentist Experience</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:22:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</guid>
      <description>This time So I was about to visit a dentist today. It was my last visit in this &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo;. And I needed to fix a wisdom tooth.
And I randomly recollected that at some point in the past when a dentist was injecting anestesia it felt like they are injecting the needle right into the bone.
And since this was my last visit I felt like experimentating and not injecting anything this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:28:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</guid>
      <description>I really like reading History of Gallic Wars by Caesar.
There are interesting small details everywhere: details about politics, contracts, warfare, decision making.
The narrative itself is also quite fascinating to me.
Also national differences that are depicted in the book are quite entertaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitement</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:56:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting insight from reading GTD is that there is a level of positive feelings you get from envisioning future results of your projects.
The level tends to go up with the clarity created by use of the process. So the need to have &amp;ldquo;artificial sweeteners&amp;rdquo; goes down.
I think that excitement is the only reasonable expectation from your projects with this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:54:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>There are two benefits I have got from starting reading the GTD book.
 The serenity that allows you to be more focused on the things at hands. Previously unstated projects have come up like a surprise.  So there is more clarity just because of these two reasons. And I eliminated some things I previously assumed to be crucial.
BTW I use org-mode to implement it. I am happy with the proccess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Abstractions</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/real-abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 11:41:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/real-abstractions/</guid>
      <description>Abstractions are real.
Brains work with them.
And you can&amp;rsquo;t ignore what goes into your brain.
Things you can&amp;rsquo;t ignore are real for you.
Reality of production is reflected in the product.
Well. That was a tricky way to state that in the ideal world code quality is measured by the quality of abstractions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Self</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/self-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 09:24:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/self-self/</guid>
      <description>There is the idea of being in the moment.
And there is also an idea of future self.
I think the real idea is to have both things reconciled into single, repeatable understanding.
Otherwise you act not in your own interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Toys</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</guid>
      <description>I want to write an argument that there is a kind of people who like intellectual toys in certain area.
Earlier they found theology to be interesting.
Later such people were playing with philosophies, ideologies like communism.
And now such people may be writing code.
So people who are into religious fundamentalism or communism should definetly try coding.
Unfortunately in code you cannot use verbal tricks or force. But the good part is that you are not subject to the constrains of the real world either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconstrained Code</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unconstrained-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 09:05:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unconstrained-code/</guid>
      <description>I was looking at what I am doing wrong with my personal projects recently. And I think that part of the problem is this unconstrained approach.
So there is the propensity in people to be blindly optimistic about something. I found mine to be interfering with the code.
So I gotta learn some good constraints.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try some very directed and formal approach with explicit principles and compromises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constrained Games</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/constrained-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:39:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/constrained-games/</guid>
      <description>Constraints in mobile games are everywhere. And they are so explicit.
I have no idea why people voluntary accept constraints. Maybe because there are &amp;ldquo;opportunities&amp;rdquo; available around the constraints.
Somebody has to make a game where number of opportunities is decreacing all the time. To observe the influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity Order</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/complexity-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 09:47:54 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/complexity-order/</guid>
      <description>The title may be ambiguous/misleading. And chances are the idea is old.
The idea is that you add complexity in the right order. I think this is the real idea behind KISS/YAGNI/etc..
For me the right/wrong here is intuitive. I need to return to it later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditating again</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 10:07:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</guid>
      <description>Background facts I have not practiced consistently. And I consumed alot of content about it at some point and have forgotten most of it.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;m getting to know meditation again. With the first breathes you get to observe/experience Tanha directly. Also the alternative &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; is available. This is something new for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative inventors</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 12:42:04 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</guid>
      <description>I hope this blog is not going to be corrupted by politics too much.
One can sign a propaganda plakat. But one cannot sign a word. How unfortunate it is that so much creativity is unattributed.
Enormous progress has been made from the old words to the new ones. Words like &amp;ldquo;free market&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pro-choice&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ABC rights&amp;rdquo;, etc&amp;hellip; Only true visionaries can see what new words the future holds for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Started this blog</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 14:04:42 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The plan is to post some stuff I do. Like what I read for example. With some analysis maybe.
Only the good stuff.
In the end I should get more invested in the stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 09:47:54 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags-menu/</guid>
      <description> code (6) experience (1) forgotten (1) games (1) gtd (2) history (1) language (1) low-iq (1) mind (1) order (8) politics (5) random (3) reading (8) thoughts (2) trying-new-stuff (1)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>