<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Picture on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/picture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Picture on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 08:14:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/picture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Cardsharps</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-cardsharps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 08:14:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-cardsharps/</guid>
      <description>I have experienced the sudden escalation effect of the picture. I wonder if background information and other pictures influenced that experience too or the picture is self-contained.&#xA;I assume this picture for me has opened the door for other works of the author. I wonder if it casts a shadow too.&#xA;Spoilers the artist was involved in stabbing a person to death over gambling matters English naming of picture sounds sharp other paintings too often have or imply sharp objects </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Et in Arcadia ego</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/et-in-arcadia-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 14:30:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/et-in-arcadia-ego/</guid>
      <description>Context I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bit distracted into different nonsense lately. Then I&amp;rsquo;ve read some Gombrich and there he features the painting. The painting straightened me up a bit.&#xA;Gombrich gives enough tips to get you to find the answer but rightfully he does not offer the direct answer himself. This way he keeps magic of art for viewers to discover on their own.&#xA;Picture I enjoyed the piece for sure. If Gombrich abstains from giving away key findings then it is a good standard to adhere for me as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suruga Street in Edo</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/suruga-street-in-edo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 19:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/suruga-street-in-edo/</guid>
      <description>Magical picture. It shows something so disconnected from the ground on one hand. On another hand it touches the human nature deeply. Monumental yet alive.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
