<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antonioni on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/antonioni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antonioni on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:36:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/antonioni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-the-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:36:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-the-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to visit this one for the second time (with rewinds both forward and back).
There are small scenes that would look arbitrary or meaningless but they are not. It is very satisfying to see the director&amp;rsquo;s play and then he confirms it too.
That picture that he nods to in the final sequence got me interested. It is a funny scene on the first look.
Another look is to compare the picture to one of the latest girl talking scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Notte</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:01:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</guid>
      <description>Just gotta make a post but there is not much I can say&amp;hellip; I decided not to write the post right after watching because I thought the next day I may get some ideas&amp;hellip;
I know this way of structuring stuff is stupid but whatever.
Pros:
Some nice shots are present Some fun, absurd or just strange scenes are there Cons:
pace is not for me messy so called &amp;ldquo;psychological&amp;rdquo; stuff about characters being unhappy and all that does not attract me ugly sounds play from time to time Notables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:37:55 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</guid>
      <description>Initially the movie seems simple then I just got to think that it is not what I undestood enough to really write something constructive.
Anyway visually I&amp;rsquo;m just too easy to impress so I liked many &amp;ldquo;shots&amp;rdquo;.
There were also some of these scenes that directors do that take your breath without something explicitly dramatic happening.
I beleive it can have rewatch value but only in some very close-watch analysis mode&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 08:46:14 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I definetly liked some scenes most notably driving throug fog.
There are some obvious things directors do:
in the beginning the face of the director is contrasted to white clouds (so you can see the a silhouette of the face in the white because of how seeing works) in the end the face of the director fades into darkness but you still see the silhouette you see water flow again - I still beleive it means flow of time/life the symbol of vase is mentioned - as something for flowers some scenes are deep and serious and some are too casual (surely intentinally but did different directors did them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:06:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</guid>
      <description>One notable thing my acquaintance with Antonioni is that how bad initial impression was. First I started watching one movie and just turned it off after having a minute or two watching at something ugly with construction sounds at the background. Now I decided to try another one and you guess what. It throws at you some totally mess of sounds during the initial credits. Then it contrasts it by some piano notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blowup</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</guid>
      <description>My first movie of the director. I have seen some time ago and now decided to give a try to works of Antonioni overall. I put there thoughts I got from it.
Scenes: In the beginning credits are shown in an interesting way you kind of see somethnig by through letters but you only see the gist. The movie starts with fun-car, and then death-camp-looking corridor - contrast from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
