<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antonioni on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/antonioni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antonioni on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 08:46:14 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/antonioni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 08:46:14 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I definetly liked some scenes most notably driving throug fog.
There are some obvious things directors do:
 in the beginning the face of the director is contrasted to white clouds (so you can see the a silhouette of the face in the white because of how seeing works) in the end the face of the director fades into darkness but you still see the silhouette you see water flow again - I still beleive it means flow of time/life the symbol of vase is mentioned - as something for flowers some scenes are deep and serious and some are too casual (surely intentinally but did different directors did them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:06:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</guid>
      <description>One notable thing my acquaintance with Antonioni is that how bad initial impression was. First I started watching one movie and just turned it off after having a minute or two watching at something ugly with construction sounds at the background. Now I decided to try another one and you guess what. It throws at you some totally mess of sounds during the initial credits. Then it contrasts it by some piano notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blowup</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</guid>
      <description>My first movie of the director. I have seen some time ago and now decided to give a try to works of Antonioni overall. I put there thoughts I got from it.
Scenes: In the beginning credits are shown in an interesting way you kind of see somethnig by through letters but you only see the gist. The movie starts with fun-car, and then death-camp-looking corridor - contrast from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
