<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>times on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/times/</link>
    <description>Recent content in times on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:07:58 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/times/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympics Idiocy</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/olympics-idiocy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 10:07:58 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/olympics-idiocy/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote that least bad scenario would be robots being made to run in masks.
But I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that people would do worse and voluntary. That error of underestimating idiocy of others I should stop committing.
Because of course some of hokey players ended-up playing in masks.
While normally the game should be very demanding and oxygen-wise too. But in these times having a good game is not valuable anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Propaganda</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sunday-propaganda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 11:43:30 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sunday-propaganda/</guid>
      <description>I have just returned from a walk. On the way back I have heared local church bells ringing. I tried to look at it and wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to see anything behind trees except some yellow glow. So these &amp;ldquo;golden-hats&amp;rdquo; the church has make it possible to see it even further. I wonder if their angle is such to cover the maximum area in early day hours.
There is another traditional thing you may be sure of on sundays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 10:28:11 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/skin/</guid>
      <description>In the old times hunters used to skin animals and sell the result.
These days animals are getting extinct and cruel pratcices are out of favor. But the skin gets even more expensive!
And with all the abundant money supply these days also. I should not be surprised when I see a skin that costs millions of dollars.
Wild times they are!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>