<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notions on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/notions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notions on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 08:24:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/notions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Genre Change</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 08:24:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</guid>
      <description>Movie-wise personally the 2022 was marked by the sign of genre change. It has started with the Witch Burned Alive enchanting piece. It progressed into the dark-aesthetics and contrasting world of Mariken van Nieumeghen.
Then I hit the inverse apex of anti-aesthetics in re-watching some old clip on some odd verses by Epifancev. Given new tools this was readable and superficial/catchy but with presence of relatively sophisticated technology. Given me being outsider to these crafts I got impressed by the experience technology used there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:21:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tolerance/</guid>
      <description>From a perspective of a random non-educated yet not-indoctrinated person notions used for public may seem too vaguely defined and thus being abused to support whatever they must.
I feel like there should be a specific subset in this notion of tolerance that is not being corrupted by the game and this is where it takes it&amp;rsquo;s power.
I like how this would mean that even questionable politicians are forced to use the right notions even if they are loading them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:35:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/democracy/</guid>
      <description>As I understand today the notion is applied to anything where elections are not obviously bought/stolen/taken by force.
And I have an impression that this word has really big halo not only among the demos but also part of some basic assumed ideology of talking/thinking classes.
Obviously it is too subvertable to be anything that can be called &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;. But the recent war shows that in competition against more &amp;ldquo;archaic&amp;rdquo; system it wins (as it looks now).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
