<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coppola on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/coppola/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coppola on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:47:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/coppola/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bram Stoker&#39;s Dracula</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/bram_stokers_dracula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 19:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/bram_stokers_dracula/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is bleeding the World of Darkness.&#xA;Indeed, if one lets their mind see the word &amp;ldquo;undead&amp;rdquo; without cliché,&#xA;then it&amp;rsquo;s apparent how unnaturally opposite to the dead it must be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initially I was skeptical, but then I accepted the primal currency.&#xA;Instead of being elaborate and artificial, it goes after natural, raw, and super-natural.&#xA;And it is fundamentally flawed, yet fundamentally true.&#xA;But once you have accepted the language of senses, the mind is bound to go mute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megalopolis</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/megalopolis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 17:28:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/megalopolis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The populus not liking the movie is a good omen for considering it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initially, I thought the movie &amp;ldquo;lacked&amp;rdquo; the canned laughter to trigger the public when they should laugh.&#xA;But then the movie delivered even that, so it got double laugh from me there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It got me into artsy bait initially, but then delivered some screwed take on The Red Shoes.&#xA;So the movie makes fun of not only consumers of trashy content but also pokes the other side of the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conversation</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 11:28:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-conversation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie has a sad subject, but it does not try to pull a tear from the viewer’s eye.&#xA;In fact, it features a mime and some funny scenes, so I wouldn’t be surprised if it’s actually a comedy.&#xA;It also features visuals of interest and a range of ambiguity, so I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to rewatch it, even though the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t force that per se.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
