<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 18:39:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apology</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 18:39:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/apology/</guid>
      <description>Overview Best known piece where Plato poses big question vividly. The question touches many topics and can be seen from different angles. Humor lightens the reading while also bringing Socrates closer thus increasing the gravity of the question.
Angles obvious to me:
 high cost of truth vs mass of conformists individual ethics vs median masses mechanics/(im)morality political/ideological: &amp;ldquo;undemocratic logic&amp;rdquo; of considering what is best as opposed to wherever masses go political/class: rich young followers intergenerational and other decay/corruption of Athens inadequate court process, circus by definition  Unforgettable quote: &amp;ldquo;by the dog I swear!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Righteous Mind</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-righteous-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 19:58:51 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-righteous-mind/</guid>
      <description>Found-out that scribd has some good stuff that I wanted to check like this title. So I got over first three chapters in audio format. Looking at how it goes I would switch to the short version in this case.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t eat while listening to it because the author does alot of stuff in the beginning for sure. I think consciously but who knows; Even though narrated by the author the experience is very copy-paste/so-conventional from the execution point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeffirelli</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zeffirelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:29:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zeffirelli/</guid>
      <description>Here I should have impressions on the works of the director.
Romeo and Juliet I&amp;rsquo;m not going to analyse the content here. Because there has to be more than enough high-quality analysis of Shakespeare.
I liked the main theme. And some scenes for sure. And almost all main characters even if they all act as possessed at different times.
One thing about the movie is that in the process it looks as overly exaggregated and theatrical (as is expected).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piano Sight Reading Mini Book</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/piano-sight-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 13:08:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/piano-sight-reading/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Open libraries are so cool. They motivate by themselves. Borrowing and kind-of a limit of time makes the book even more attractive.
Here I just do own notes to review them after I finished reading. It is not something pretending to have been carefully extracted and distilled. Sometimes in the process I just do not record stuff, sometimes I record alot more.
The Book Piano, Guided Sight-Reading. [A New Approach to Piano Study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2020</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 09:50:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/february-2020/</guid>
      <description>Reading Concerning reading/audio I have finished Orthodoxy. I wanted to write about it but it is not the case that I am 100% sure about my own view on these topics. Anyway there is a lot of good stuff in the book overall.
Basically the author likes his choice/experience and consistency is not the only value he needs. Although in public policy I would be aganist things like that. Even though author mildly argues for that also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2020</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/january-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 18:36:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/january-2020/</guid>
      <description>I almost stopped reading stuff so I didn&amp;rsquo;t write about anything interesting.
Although I have started listening to Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Orthodoxy and I have given couple of small attempts to continue/restart reading Droyzen and Livy. I&amp;rsquo;m not doing it methodically and I&amp;rsquo;m not really in control of personal time now.
So I decided to write about what I have in mind to address that.
First there is an app idea that I develop when I feel like and then I move to something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; Hear me today discoursing in the house of Quadratus.
&amp;ndash; Why should I hear you? Do you wish to show me that you put words together cleverly? You put them together man. And what good will it do you?
 So I have finished listening to an audiobook of teachings of Epictetus. The audiobook is performed by Hayward Morse.
The content is both very sober, straightforward and logical as it is also entertaining and with a lot of humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 18:00:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>I knew about the guy previously but I was avoiding getting into his stuff at all. But this time I decided to look into his content.
First I got into some debate youtube videos of him. And it was ok.
So I decided to look into his audiobook.
I found the first part quite informative for me:
 I really like biological facts about how things work Christianity as a big sacrafice was new information for me I also enjoyed different literary excerpts (Dostoevsky and others)  But then after 50% the real fun starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Lies</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</guid>
      <description>While reading Marxism by T. Sowell I cought myself on thoughts that the stuff is not as ugly as what is claimed to be applications of it. The stuff even felt attractive in theory.
So I quickly visited one site to see what ideas are there these days.
What I found is some pool of mud filled with red-herrings and repeated talking points. It didn&amp;rsquo;t look that the writers are entirely dumb but that they are a bit psychotic and very ideological and partisan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D and D</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 20:04:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of things that I noticed while reading &amp;ldquo;Discrimination and Disparities&amp;rdquo; by T. Sowell.
Obviously the authour is a very logical and factual no BS guy.
The book is full of tricks politicans use and facts they tend to hide.
I noticed this disambiguation of the term &amp;ldquo;discrimination&amp;rdquo; by the author:
 evidence based discrimination (1A): based on knowledge of traits and behavior of a given individual evidence based discrimination (1B): based on statistics on group behavior, traits arbitrary discrimination (2): arbitrary/irrational  This is how I understood this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tar Pit</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:27:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write short summary and some ideas after reading &amp;ldquo;Out of the Tar Pit&amp;rdquo;.
Summary It looks like a theoretical high level paper about comlexity in large codebases.
The main point can be statend in the form: eliminate stuff/separate certain parts of the system to reduce power/ability to introduce accedintal complexity.
What is being separated: essential state, essential logic, control.
Also proposed ways to implement these parts:
 state - relaitons logic - pure functions  My Thoughts I am pretty convinced that relations are the way to go for the essential state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:28:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</guid>
      <description>I really like reading History of Gallic Wars by Caesar.
There are interesting small details everywhere: details about politics, contracts, warfare, decision making.
The narrative itself is also quite fascinating to me.
Also national differences that are depicted in the book are quite entertaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitement</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:56:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting insight from reading GTD is that there is a level of positive feelings you get from envisioning future results of your projects.
The level tends to go up with the clarity created by use of the process. So the need to have &amp;ldquo;artificial sweeteners&amp;rdquo; goes down.
I think that excitement is the only reasonable expectation from your projects with this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:54:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>There are two benefits I have got from starting reading the GTD book.
 The serenity that allows you to be more focused on the things at hands. Previously unstated projects have come up like a surprise.  So there is more clarity just because of these two reasons. And I eliminated some things I previously assumed to be crucial.
BTW I use org-mode to implement it. I am happy with the proccess.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
