<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:28:45 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:28:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</guid>
      <description>I really like reading History of Gallic Wars by Caesar.
There are interesting small details everywhere: details about politics, contracts, warfare, decision making.
The narrative itself is also quite fascinating to me.
Also national differences that are depicted in the book are quite entertaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitement</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:56:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting insight from reading GTD is that there is a level of positive feelings you get from envisioning future results of your projects.
The level tends to go up with the clarity created by use of the process. So the need to have &amp;ldquo;artificial sweeteners&amp;rdquo; goes down.
I think that excitement is the only reasonable expectation from your projects with this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:54:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>There are two benefits I have got from starting reading the GTD book.
 The serenity that allows you to be more focused on the things at hands. Previously unstated projects have come up like a surprise.  So there is more clarity just because of these two reasons. And I eliminated some things I previously assumed to be crucial.
BTW I use org-mode to implement it. I am happy with the proccess.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>