<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zeffirelli on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/zeffirelli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zeffirelli on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 21:11:13 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/zeffirelli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Callas Forever</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 21:11:13 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</guid>
      <description>First, I watched it in three sessions as planned.
The beginning predictably left me not excited. The movie provides some words to describe it: &amp;ldquo;too modern&amp;rdquo;. And the word &amp;ldquo;flat&amp;rdquo; came to my mind too. No idea why. I will figure-out one day: is it me or is it how they are made.
At the end of the first third you get to see some development and get intrigued by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Watch</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 05:25:11 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</guid>
      <description>I have noticed that watching in two sessions worked for me well with two Zeffirelli movies (Sparrow, Hamlet).
It can be either due to the way he made movies or due to the way at least my attention works.
Currently I lean to the second option and I also think that this half-watch experience provides similar value as rewatching: more details or connections are being noticed.
I think that it works this way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparrow</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 18:44:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</guid>
      <description>Watched this one in two sessions and the decision worked well. Because about the first session I got the impression that the movie is too much into this suffering thing. And that I&amp;rsquo;m not the right audience for the theme overall. And it surely has those aspects but there are more interesting things and ideas going on.
During the second fresh session I immediately noticed nice directors work. At one point he shot it like it is actually in the space above the planet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
