<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visual on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/visual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visual on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:34:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/visual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Langscape</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/langscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:34:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/langscape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;langscape&#34;&gt;Langscape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t read much so my verbal faculty is likely more affected by programming than by stories.&#xA;More affected by reflection than by communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way I use language in these posts is in a way minimalistic and analytical.&#xA;I assume the text file supports the brain working memory.&#xA;That maybe frees some pattern recognition resources.&#xA;And recognizing patterns should build the ability to recognize them in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So my verbal space is always incomplete at least culturally.&#xA;And since I started writing these posts it is always in the backlog for potential work-in-progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 19:42:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/inheritance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the previous year I got to read some of Igor Guberman short but sharp writings.&#xA;They are often smart and touch on different topics while they can easily contain raw language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this year I got to check short-form writings by Piet Hein.&#xA;I thought that there is likely to be an inheritance/influence between the authors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First is obviously similar short form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second is political angle.&#xA;As I understand Piet Hein wrote generally interesting pieces but with contextual second meanings relevant to German occupation of Denmark of that time.&#xA;Igor Guberman writing is more open and costed him imprisonment in Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Dragon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ghost-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 17:22:19 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ghost-dragon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in a day I liked heroes of might and magic game.&#xA;Overall it was not right to get me addicted but I really liked some parts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing I found odd is that there are like ten types of dragons.&#xA;Most of them I considered to be nonsensical - created just to fill some gaps in ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One particular kind of dragons I liked irrationally is the Skeleton Dragon that can be upgraded to the Ghost Dragon.&#xA;I liked it on one hand for no apparent reason.&#xA;But I found it odd that you upgrade a material thing to something ephemeral and that thing gets stronger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Painting Still Life in Gouache</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/painting-still-life-in-gouache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 10:49:29 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/painting-still-life-in-gouache/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon this one even though it was not one on the recommendations list.&#xA;I just got to like it and finished.&#xA;Touches different aspects without staying there for too long.&#xA;Has nice quotes and seduces you with colorful images.&#xA;Seems nice for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrast</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 20:08:32 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/contrast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is one simple thing I remember from an art class in school days.&#xA;It can be summarized this way: I didn&amp;rsquo;t beleive that a thing in dark background looks brighter.&#xA;And that unresolved question informed some my decisions later while experimenting with that.&#xA;But it is something that is still not resolved in a way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today while I was walking around the city there were three occasions when I just got kind of surprised by beauty of some view.&#xA;And in these occasions preceding view was very different and in a way contrasted to the next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
