<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurosawa on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kurosawa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kurosawa on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:46:33 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kurosawa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ikiru</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ikiru/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:46:33 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ikiru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched both Ikiru and The Blob on the same day.&#xA;And then finished it with Pee-wee&amp;rsquo;s Big Adventure.&#xA;Now I&amp;rsquo;ll need to live with this, so I need to rethink this blog&amp;rsquo;s philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe it will be ratings blog.&#xA;So I&amp;rsquo;ll rate them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ikiru goes first because rabbits can jump and they&amp;rsquo;d smash the competitors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Blob takes the second place because it destroys dinosaurs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pee-wee is the last because he was riding in the wrong direction&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Throne of Blood</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/throne-of-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:56:11 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/throne-of-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One characteristic childhood memory I have is, when I asked why Chinese have narrow eyes,&#xA;I was told that because they are smart,&#xA;so I started to walk around and operate with my eyes as closest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think some far eastern, concise, ambiguous/imaginative, probably explicitly wisdom/educational stories impressed me at some point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throne of Blood, even if it is based on Shakespeare seems to be distilled in that minimalistic style.&#xA;Even black and white format supports the austerity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rashomon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/rashomon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:39:18 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/rashomon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason my headset decided to play it at the half-speed.&#xA;I thought that timing goes wrong but didn&amp;rsquo;t care to check properly so I thought it was a director&amp;rsquo;s style decision to make it that way.&#xA;The sound is very unusual, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m going to watch this movie normally after that experience.&#xA;And it fits the beginning so much, so I fell in love with the movie right away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Samurai</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/seven-samurai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:13:59 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/seven-samurai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After finishing the movie, I saw a dream resembling Wolf of Wall Street&#xA;but with a limited palette, and it was unclear who was more high - the main characters or the more normal people around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My take is that the movie is high.&#xA;You can see they had fun doing it.&#xA;Also it has wisdom elements and construction so I did the second watch/scroll to refine the details there.&#xA;In that lane the movie is a potent meditation on human character traits and human action in abstract.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
