<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubrick on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kubrick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubrick on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:30:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kubrick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2001: A Space Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:30:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The simpler/more-explicit movie so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to stick to just first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I expected the movie to be about cardinal topic.&#xA;The topic is human state and experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;spoilers-if-you-like&#34;&gt;Spoilers if you like&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The topic is shown from two angles overimposed: intelligence and reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The black rectangular prism means evolution crossing some limit.&#xA;All four key appearances signify something fundamental to human experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First: &amp;ldquo;monkeys&amp;rdquo; get natural intelligence evolved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second: superficially - artificial intelligence gets discovered, but I&amp;rsquo;d say there is more to that AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third: is experience of body generation complexity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fourth: is limit of unacheivable by every previous generation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie feels very humane at certain moments dispite it being not the most cozy watch.&#xA;Understanding the whole thing makes it a comedy too.&#xA;This makes for an interesting depth in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes Wide Shut</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:45:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of this director and I recall some things to be interesting&#xA;I otherwise avoided watching his work because the name seemed too popular.&#xA;Checked this one for a random reason.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about the choice for the first half maybe.&#xA;But then the director delivered technically.&#xA;And then I got to see the conception that is brilliant too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Delivered in colorful and crinkling packaging to distract the viewer;&#xA;simultaneously Christmas and Halloween joke played right on the viewer;&#xA;yet also having a personal down to earth snapshot of not obvious family business management at one point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
