<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubrick on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kubrick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubrick on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 11:27:35 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/kubrick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fidelio</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/fidelio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 11:27:35 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/fidelio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whatever random public wrongly feels about the movie,&#xA;it really represents the director&amp;rsquo;s fidelity to the arts.&#xA;I expect to get around the 4K and have a blast closer to the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The used cover art is on the disgusting side from the point of view above.&#xA;But it&amp;rsquo;s what you expect from a jealous wife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Torque</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/torque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:59:16 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/torque/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TLDR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digging maze vs actually solving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-missing&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s missing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original Avocaat Party post was written on the spot and was not as analytical but more descriptive.&#xA;Also I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the implications of it anyway.&#xA;So here, I try to integrate my understanding concisely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;correction&#34;&gt;Correction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If Rosemary&amp;rsquo;s Baby gives you a stab, digging into The Shining will stab you and then rotate the knife inside.&#xA;Seven months on the wagon, I think I got back to the starting point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnum Opus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/magnum-opus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 20:03:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/magnum-opus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Less than five months on the wagon and I think I have satisfactory solution to The Shining.&#xA;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the tenth such realization over time, but the latest pieces of the puzzle weren&amp;rsquo;t rotating the whole picture,&#xA;which does not make them less powerful and brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is the magnum opus and unreachable peak in the medium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Killing</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-killing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 10:21:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-killing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good transparent fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Months on the Wagon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/four-months-on-the-wagon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:11:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/four-months-on-the-wagon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four months since the first conscious meeting with The Shining,&#xA;and I&amp;rsquo;m still afflicted by solving aspects of it.&#xA;Even though I took a break at one point, now I think I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my approach.&#xA;My approach now is more goal/question-oriented, so it is more constrained.&#xA;Still, the movie can even enter dreams in some abstract way.&#xA;So I&amp;rsquo;m drawn to look into abstraction, and it gratifies, I think.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were some interesting photographs posted recently, so it is a good point to report on the progress(ion).&#xA;While also pouring some reds into the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lolita</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lolita/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:56:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lolita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeez what a picture.&#xA;The most devious spoilers coming along.&#xA;The reader must close this page immediately,&#xA;at the risk of breathtaking details being revealed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have read to this line,&#xA;then this is the last warning.&#xA;I repeat: this is the last warning!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, so you have crossed the line.&#xA;Now all bets are off.&#xA;But be careful, because on the judgment day you may be asked: &amp;ldquo;Did you watch the movie? Or did you read about it?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casablanca</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/casablanca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 15:22:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/casablanca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I liked how the picture was made; it is necessary to see it from that perspective.&#xA;But as it happens when the viewer reduces the picture to their own level of thinking,&#xA;I shall proceed and make this post about alcohol in movies I saw relatively recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is so much alcohol in Casablanca that movie disc boxes should be tagged with excise taxes.&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that final bottle drop has any subconscious effect from that perspective,&#xA;but I observed some dynamics in my own relation to alcohol that was changing with the level of conscious understanding of other pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Choking</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-choking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 09:44:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-choking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To solve is to reduce complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given an ambiguous picture,&#xA;It looks like what one considers to be the solution is formed by a sequence of what one considers to be bigger insights or stimuli the person could see.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I considered The Shining to be generally solved as I saw it for some time.&#xA;But the picture always leaves some breadcrumbs one can follow further into it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now my impression is that opportunities are seemingly infinite in it.&#xA;So one can read the picture similar to reading coffee residue.&#xA;At some point I get too much caffeine to the extent that it physically does not feel good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAL Moment</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hal-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 12:56:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hal-moment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got to have a point, where the only way to express it is by quoting some of the HAL monologue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiments on People</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/experiments-on-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:34:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/experiments-on-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;point&#34;&gt;Point&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experiments reveal something about the subject.&#xA;Among other things these three definetly have the viewer as their subject too: 2001: A Space Odyssey, The Shining, Eyes Wide Shut.&#xA;Also those movies are talked about more broadly than understood, so this makes for some interesting social experiment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My observations at this point:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;people use different strategies and faculties for solving these movies and it is very contextual&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there is almost a protection mechanism around the &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo;, that is &amp;ldquo;understood&amp;rdquo; by all parties, in part because &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo; is realized in executing those strategies, not in completing the search&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lately thinking about the idea of shadow archetype-wise very abstractly.&#xA;Looking into these dynamics is in a way that shadow area for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Shining</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-shining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:04:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-shining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mist&#34;&gt;Mist&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t recall my first experience of the movie.&#xA;So there is this interesting state when you got some cinema literacy and&#xA;may have the illusion that you can&amp;rsquo;t see it with fresh eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe the whole remote Hotel theme invokes that feeling that there&#xA;are experiences remote in the past that you can&amp;rsquo;t even recall, not to say about making sense of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;realism&#34;&gt;Realism&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I watched the movie in a headset.&#xA;I generally control fear response by having controlled volume and being analytical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2001: A Space Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:30:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The simpler/more-explicit movie so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to stick to just first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I expected the movie to be about cardinal topic.&#xA;The topic is human state and experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;spoilers-if-you-like&#34;&gt;Spoilers if you like&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The topic is shown from two angles overimposed: intelligence and reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The black rectangular prism means evolution crossing some limit.&#xA;All four key appearances signify something fundamental to human experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First: &amp;ldquo;monkeys&amp;rdquo; get natural intelligence evolved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second: superficially - artificial intelligence gets discovered, but I&amp;rsquo;d say there is more to that AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third: is experience of body generation complexity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fourth: is limit of unacheivable by every previous generation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie feels very humane at certain moments dispite it being not the most cozy watch.&#xA;Understanding the whole thing makes it a comedy too.&#xA;This makes for an interesting depth in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes Wide Shut</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:45:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of this director and I recall some things to be interesting&#xA;I otherwise avoided watching his work because the name seemed too popular.&#xA;Checked this one for a random reason.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about the choice for the first half maybe.&#xA;But then the director delivered technically.&#xA;And then I got to see the conception that is brilliant too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Delivered in colorful and crinkling packaging to distract the viewer;&#xA;simultaneously Christmas and Halloween joke played right on the viewer;&#xA;yet also having a personal down to earth snapshot of not obvious family business management at one point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
