<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenders on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/wenders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wenders on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/wenders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the Face</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a breaking of the fourth wall element in theater/cinema.&#xA;I recall the name only after I start to see significance of such tools.&#xA;For example, in Killer&amp;rsquo;s of the Flower Moon, there are at least two sneaky breakings of the fourth wall&#xA;and one obvious one at the end.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d say, even if sneaky, they signify key moments to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For whatever questionable reason, I watched Perfect Days by Wim Wenders too recently.&#xA;Somehow, the director, even if the he has great work, tends to be mentioned by Russian speaking people who signal sophistication.&#xA;And I&amp;rsquo;m fine if somebody references, at least after watching it, if the reference is good.&#xA;But in that case, the referencer probably asked chat-gpt and got hallucinated and confused mix of stuff.&#xA;So it was the worst possible reference, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to think about that.&#xA;(BTW: I use chat-gpt to put commas around; hopefully, that does not make my references bad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Himmel über Berlin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/der-himmel-uber-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 21:11:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/der-himmel-uber-berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though the pace of the movie may be not too fast and given certain melancholy and lots of internal monologues there.&#xA;After watching the movie it actually left positive if not optimistic and very humane impression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 10-th minute there is explicit visual play with reflected lights.&#xA;And this sets the standard and expectation.&#xA;So the viewer is practically encouraged to analyze other visuals used.&#xA;But also that play by itself may worth a rewatch or two after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Clouds</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-the-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 19:36:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/beyond-the-clouds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to visit this one for the second time (with rewinds both forward and back).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are small scenes that would look arbitrary or meaningless but they are not.&#xA;It is very satisfying to see the director&amp;rsquo;s play and then he confirms it too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That picture that he nods to in the final sequence got me interested.&#xA;It is a funny scene on the first look.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another look is to compare the picture to one of the latest girl talking scenes.&#xA;That brings starting monologue of the director.&#xA;Then ultimately compare it to the final shot through the window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blues</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:52:57 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking into Blues and got this series produced by Scorsese.&#xA;I liked Vinyl series so checking this too sounded like a good idea.&#xA;I watch it in the order of my own relevance/preference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The part by Clint Eastwood got me interested from some unexpected angle.&#xA;Most of the time music itself did not attract me.&#xA;And that got me interested even more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly he tried to capture some of that atmosphere so brought those characters to convey it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
