<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pressburger on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/pressburger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pressburger on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/pressburger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Made in England: the Films of Powell and Pressburger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</guid>
      <description>As any good film this documentary addresses different audiences&amp;rsquo; interests.&#xA;It could be seen as an overview and an introduction to the cinema of Powel and Pressburger also branded The Archers. I like how creative paths of that collaboration and M. Scorsese are interwoven in different ways. So, it can be seen as double documentary to some extent.&#xA;Of course this is not a documentary in any dull sense because the subject cinema is so creative, expressive and strong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matter of Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>Hypnotic start and common but strange finish.&#xA;Sometimes things not said or not shown are interesting.&#xA;Here I see ideas about thunderbolt, neuron growth, ladder, and &amp;ldquo;flight from Berlin&amp;rdquo;. Also script should have some ideas that did not make it into the movie.&#xA;There is propaganda angle to it which is fine by me. I think it is still strong even if the idea of Anglo-American cooperation in the new world is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Narcissus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</guid>
      <description>It is a type of lucid Disney movie crossing into a horror film. The earliest erotic movie. Melodrama about nuns.&#xA;Spoilers may lie ahead.&#xA;Team In director&amp;rsquo;s commentary M. Powell mentions:&#xA;high quality of the team and art department cases of intrinsic match of actors to roles directors role of believing in the project how the team kind of lived through the movie (without big picture possibly?) And this final point probably assumes a degree of improvisation on actors part in the process and also a degree of freedom during the editing part.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeping Tom</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 15:36:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</guid>
      <description>Spoiler alert and all that.&#xA;I watched Peeping Tom a couple of weeks ago. It is now or never I should write-down what I thought about it.&#xA;Key points many things at once is how I see it the idea that fear is the scariest thing is liberating lots of visual language, some just makes you puzzled, some is obvious it succeeded at confusing me at points surely effect: not scared but puzzled (which is good, scaredness would inhibit analysis) high contrast movie: hilarious/odd/interesting scenes, different personalities, direct contrast and directors tools can be seen or you just feel their presence even if not sure what exactly is there; fearless desensitized vs fearless normal magic camera aspect I have not resolved - some positive vision probably topic of desensitization by the industry enjoyed accents Quality all this baits you in for partial-rewatch even though there is some empuzzlement and repulsion present as a general feeling but the director did his work by quality in all regards to cover for the theme effect; the movie is like a shopping stall of goods about directing things and producing effects, &amp;ldquo;things perceptable and the general level is not distracting your from products&amp;rdquo;, so there should be rewatch value from that for sure; it is not at all an ADHD fast-paced salad so you have your time to think about stuff, I liked that for sure, yet it leaves an impresson of being filled with quality material; Exceprts That &amp;ldquo;he is the director&amp;rdquo; I understood it (but not at that moment) as both:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
