<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Textual on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/textual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Textual on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 14:21:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/textual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Book</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-read-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 14:21:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-read-a-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;then&#34;&gt;Then&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I try to install a habit for reading from time to time.&#xA;Previous attempt was Faust that weights 2 kilos because of big format and stylistically different but exceptional pictures on every other page.&#xA;Such pictures were competing with images in the text but I enjoyed both.&#xA;One notable experience such book can give is when you are trying to analyze through some text&#xA;and turn the page and see some unexpected picture.&#xA;Then this picture can sink your active attention as some exit that you grasp and appreciate like you would not expect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 19:42:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/inheritance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the previous year I got to read some of Igor Guberman short but sharp writings.&#xA;They are often smart and touch on different topics while they can easily contain raw language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this year I got to check short-form writings by Piet Hein.&#xA;I thought that there is likely to be an inheritance/influence between the authors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First is obviously similar short form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second is political angle.&#xA;As I understand Piet Hein wrote generally interesting pieces but with contextual second meanings relevant to German occupation of Denmark of that time.&#xA;Igor Guberman writing is more open and costed him imprisonment in Soviet Union.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
