<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collective on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/collective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collective on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 09:46:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/collective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polar Positions</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/polar-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 09:46:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/polar-positions/</guid>
      <description>On one hand I see that there is value in presence of actually polar positions. While on the other hand any polar by itself is likely to be destructive.&#xA;It is odd how this balance necessitates both polarization and tolerance. Operational democracy is a demanding beast.&#xA;Note I don&amp;rsquo;t pursue the topic systematically while complexities of it get my attention periodically. So I highlight some aspects that look new to me but since I don&amp;rsquo;t have a bigger picture yet there is a higher risk of misinterpretation and inherent incompleteness of statements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:21:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tolerance/</guid>
      <description>From a perspective of a random non-educated yet not-indoctrinated person notions used for public may seem too vaguely defined and thus being abused to support whatever they must.&#xA;I feel like there should be a specific subset in this notion of tolerance that is not being corrupted by the game and this is where it takes it&amp;rsquo;s power.&#xA;I like how this would mean that even questionable politicians are forced to use the right notions even if they are loading them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 08:35:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/democracy/</guid>
      <description>As I understand today the notion is applied to anything where elections are not obviously bought/stolen/taken by force.&#xA;And I have an impression that this word has really big halo not only among the demos but also part of some basic assumed ideology of talking/thinking classes.&#xA;Obviously it is too subvertable to be anything that can be called &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo;. But the recent war shows that in competition against more &amp;ldquo;archaic&amp;rdquo; system it wins (as it looks now).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
