<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>space on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in space on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 09:27:24 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuity of Space</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/continuity-of-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 09:27:24 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/continuity-of-space/</guid>
      <description>So this is one of those posts with such name that only me can guess the content and also only while I have the idea in focus.
Abstract:
time is not really continuous since it is a sequence of different events there may be something like subjective that persists through time but it is not as evident so you can&amp;rsquo;t put your attention on it the space around us is what is actually persistent and there are natural faculties of observation and memory about it active attention is what I mean in the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Origin Flight</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:19:56 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blue/</guid>
      <description>So yesterday was the flight and I wanted to put some obvious observations here and mostly comparsion with Virgin Galactic flight about a week ago.
I only go from comparsion point of view because it makes it easy.
So first striking difference was that VG used Mr. Colbert to host the show while BO had some way more serious most of the time.
Altohugh I must say that one comic thing BO show host was doing repeatedly is reminding about Karman line in different ways and one time she even instantly followed Karman line remark with big windows remark.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
