<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Space on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/space/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:34:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Langscape</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/langscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 09:34:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/langscape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;langscape&#34;&gt;Langscape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t read much so my verbal faculty is likely more affected by programming than by stories.&#xA;More affected by reflection than by communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way I use language in these posts is in a way minimalistic and analytical.&#xA;I assume the text file supports the brain working memory.&#xA;That maybe frees some pattern recognition resources.&#xA;And recognizing patterns should build the ability to recognize them in general.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So my verbal space is always incomplete at least culturally.&#xA;And since I started writing these posts it is always in the backlog for potential work-in-progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuity of Space</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/continuity-of-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 09:27:24 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/continuity-of-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is one of those posts with such name that only me can guess the content and also only while I have the idea in focus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;time is not really continuous since it is a sequence of different events&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there may be something like subjective that persists through time but it is not as evident so you can&amp;rsquo;t put your attention on it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the space around us is what is actually persistent&#xA;and there are natural faculties of observation and memory about it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;active attention is what I mean in the post. It requires some more yet gratifies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it can be bigger or smaller space and it produces it&amp;rsquo;s own value&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I feel like making an argument that continuity of self is&#xA;created by continuity of space around us.&#xA;And therefore architecture, trees and other environment are actually living parts of individuals that live there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Origin Flight</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 06:19:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So yesterday was the flight and I wanted to put some obvious observations here and mostly comparsion with Virgin Galactic flight about a week ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I only go from comparsion point of view because it makes it easy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So first striking difference was that VG used Mr. Colbert to host the show while BO had some way more serious most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Altohugh I must say that one comic thing BO show host was doing repeatedly is reminding about Karman line in different ways and one time she even instantly followed Karman line remark with big windows remark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
