<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>politics on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:09:06 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Collective Lies</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</guid>
      <description>While reading Marxism by T. Sowell I cought myself on thoughts that the stuff is not as ugly as what is claimed to be applications of it. The stuff even felt attractive in theory.
So I quickly visited one site to see what ideas are there these days.
What I found is some pool of mud filled with red-herrings and repeated talking points. It didn&amp;rsquo;t look that the writers are entirely dumb but that they are a bit psychotic and very ideological and partisan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D and D</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 20:04:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of things that I noticed while reading &amp;ldquo;Discrimination and Disparities&amp;rdquo; by T. Sowell.
Obviously the authour is a very logical and factual no BS guy.
The book is full of tricks politicans use and facts they tend to hide.
I noticed this disambiguation of the term &amp;ldquo;discrimination&amp;rdquo; by the author:
 evidence based discrimination (1A): based on knowledge of traits and behavior of a given individual evidence based discrimination (1B): based on statistics on group behavior, traits arbitrary discrimination (2): arbitrary/irrational  This is how I understood this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das Right</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 09:39:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; is the most prominent example of language abuse for politics sake.
 It is short and not some yet another pseudo scientific &amp;ldquo;-ism&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;-fobia&amp;rdquo;. So it looks more natural on the outset; It has &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; in it :) You can create new &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; every day by adding different perfixes; You can use it to extract something from somebody; Since it is vague term it can have broad uses especially when it comes to general public; It also informs users on how to act/behave when demanding something from others: righteously;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Toys</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</guid>
      <description>I want to write an argument that there is a kind of people who like intellectual toys in certain area.
Earlier they found theology to be interesting.
Later such people were playing with philosophies, ideologies like communism.
And now such people may be writing code.
So people who are into religious fundamentalism or communism should definetly try coding.
Unfortunately in code you cannot use verbal tricks or force. But the good part is that you are not subject to the constrains of the real world either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative inventors</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 12:42:04 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</guid>
      <description>I hope this blog is not going to be corrupted by politics too much.
One can sign a propaganda plakat. But one cannot sign a word. How unfortunate it is that so much creativity is unattributed.
Enormous progress has been made from the old words to the new ones. Words like &amp;ldquo;free market&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pro-choice&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ABC rights&amp;rdquo;, etc&amp;hellip; Only true visionaries can see what new words the future holds for us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
