<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>movies on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in movies on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:44:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emilie Muller</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/emilie-muller/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:44:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/emilie-muller/</guid>
      <description>Spoilers and all  how to dominate audition without dominating it how to sell oneself without selling oneself how fools are given once in a lifetime random opportunity and how they loose it assuming that black and white is used to invoke some spirit of old stars and this is contrasted to this gray whatever that fails to catch one enjoyable very direct format  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les Miserables</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/les-miserables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 09:28:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/les-miserables/</guid>
      <description>On the outside it is a music box that is visually tasty and theatrical. When you open it you are there for multitude of melodies of crying among other serious and humorous lines.
This may make an impression of some femininity aspect or certain serious non-seriousness, naivete and oversimplification/cliche-even or even offensive to somebody&amp;rsquo;s perception of normal and mirror-neurons abuse.
Offended crowd is not the one worth listening to but still perception of such toys may need the right mindset that they don&amp;rsquo;t possess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genre Change</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 08:24:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</guid>
      <description>Path Movie-wise personally the 2022 was marked by the sign of genre change. It has started with the Witch Burned Alive enchanting piece. It progressed into the dark-aesthetics and contrasting world of Mariken van Nieumeghen.
Then I hit the inverse apex of anti-aesthetics in re-watching some old clip on some odd verses by Epifancev. Given new tools this was readable and superficial/catchy but with presence of relatively sophisticated technology. Surely there can be different readings but I got one slice that makes experience easy and does not cause any kind of stackoverflows while having enough consistency and enough new learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mariken van Nieumeghen</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mariken-van-nieumeghen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 11:18:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mariken-van-nieumeghen/</guid>
      <description>Deep and raw fish of a picture with strokes of celestial. May be dark at times and thus not for any audience and mood.
The director is a master of visual language. This is why the movie is rewatchable and rich.
I&amp;rsquo;ll just mention one scene.
The director talks straight: right above a door that Mariken enters he puts an exclamation mark with light and shadows. After that you see details that are necessary but I&amp;rsquo;ll skip them to not elaborate further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memento</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 05:17:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</guid>
      <description>Context I ended-up watching some movies recently. One of them ended-up being Memento. Movies were good but I had no idea for a post until yesterday.
Idea The idea is that things that are not expressed may end-up being non-existing in the first place. This may not be an idea behind the movie but this is the idea behind the post in its way.
Movie The movie is an interesting patchwork of scenes that go in reverse chronological order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planet Parade</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/planet-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 20:22:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/planet-parade/</guid>
      <description>Summary Good soviet movie about middle-aged males gathering for a trip. The viewer has lots of moments of reflection on deep matters of existence and life. Offering nostalgia and sharpened sense of time.
Context The movie was mentioned on Arestovich&amp;rsquo;s program twice AFAIK. So that added it to my list.
Normally after having listened to some classics it is especially hard to get me interesting in a soviet movie with military theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Lights</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/city-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:15:56 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/city-lights/</guid>
      <description>Some Context Got the bats flu the most recent stemm as it seems. Charlie Chaplin was on my list to check - out. So the opportunity to do that was realized.
Also Charlie Chaplin is such a phenomenon. And there is this familiarity to his character that you develop. So it feels totally ok to just use Charlie.
City Lights Touching story. Wery well played. Enjoyed the comedy.
Charlie had his own independent studio at the time of shooting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;oro Di Napoli</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loro-di-napoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 20:58:13 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loro-di-napoli/</guid>
      <description>This is not the first time I see this. But I like it when I see how tools of craftsman are being used. It makes things more understandable and more like communication.
So I liked how director emphasises certain places. That anchor then can reappear in memory later while adding to the experience. Or even offering small rewatch opportunity.
Also I liked how in one episode some theme from the preceeding one was confirmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Le Streghe (Visconti part)</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/le-streghe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 20:16:51 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/le-streghe/</guid>
      <description>Spoilers Land
The movie has multiple parts. I accidentially started watching the one by Visconti that I had already seen at that point and got sucked-in. And then to write more gave another look. And then I could not resisit another look&amp;hellip;
The setting is in the Alps. Alot of botanical framed pictures everywhere represent the topic on the walls. Lack of acquaintance with arts limits the viewer at different points&amp;hellip; Red color is favored there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Il Giovane Toscanini</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-giovane-toscanini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 11:08:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-giovane-toscanini/</guid>
      <description>There are always visuals that I enjoy in Zeffirelli movies and I think it is just my taste being very simple in a way. I&amp;rsquo;m not at the point where I can be specific about visual styles of directors.
The plot offers a streak of victories to the protagonist.
 First at La Scala when he gets a better opportinity where he is more valued; Second when he revives the diva; Third when he again exchanges the conventional success for the soulmate and a new undertaking; And then becomes a conductor too, saving and even altering the performance, making it feel more like a historic event;  I think one theme that goes through the movie is how new generation finds and takes it&amp;rsquo;s place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon of Desert</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 13:02:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</guid>
      <description>I watched alot of stuff in 2021 that I&amp;rsquo;d like to write something about just to see how it goes. But there should be a starting point somewhere and the most recent movie is the subject of the post.
The movie is short so the post should follow the shape of the movie.
What I have seen is lots of patches with with some light humour everywhere in between. Patches are different and that may be confusing because it looks like there are serious topics interwoven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blues</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:52:57 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</guid>
      <description>Looking into Blues and got this series produced by Scorsese. I liked Vinyl series so checking this too sounded like a good idea. I watch it in the order of my own relevance/preference.
 The part by Clint Eastwood got me interested from some unexpected angle. Most of the time music itself did not attract me. And that got me interested even more.
Possibly he tried to capture some of that atmosphere so brought those characters to convey it for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Otto E Mezzo</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/otto-e-mezzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 12:27:38 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/otto-e-mezzo/</guid>
      <description>You see quality from the start. A movie about life and play that says it for itself.
From the director tools point of view I have noticed that the director conveys some things before actualy revealing them. So there is a rewatch value added just by that.
Also some scenes are spectacular for unknown reasons - this must have been studied well already. But that I think is not what plain rewatch helps with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagliacci</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/pagliacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 18:26:56 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/pagliacci/</guid>
      <description>Watched this one without knowledge of libretto and without understanding of language and that was not the best idea.
Visually and overall I&amp;rsquo;m attracted to the topic of such strange wandering performers. But as very often happens - you get the shape but there is something else joined to it and you don&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the thing you expected initially. So one may think that the first thing was there just to create an illusion of something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cavalleria Rusticana</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cavalleria-rusticana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 21:31:12 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cavalleria-rusticana/</guid>
      <description>Watched it without subtitles or anything. Actually didn&amp;rsquo;t even know the libretto and the name of what I was watching.
Normally tragedy is not the genre I watch or even understand. I&amp;rsquo;m repulced by the ending of Lakme for example. Some things should not be played because they can&amp;rsquo;t be played truthfully I believe. But probably I&amp;rsquo;m getting to be more open minded about the genre.
This time I found myself being very empathetic to Elena Obrazcova so I believe she played well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Joe Black</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/meet-joe-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 21:05:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/meet-joe-black/</guid>
      <description>You see the good quality there. There is class I believe too.
One can say that the play is very detailed. Even this that is not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to capture but it is definetly visible.
The topic touched is often serious so to move to another scene the director has small humorous scenes.
Overall pace may be slow and the length is longish. At some points you may think: &amp;ldquo;What kind of dialogs are these?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus of Nazareth (upd: final episode)</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jesus-of-nazareth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:30:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jesus-of-nazareth/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: spoils may lie ahead.
I watched only the first part of fourth at this point.
 like I guess all Zeffirelli movies this one has beautiful nature shots also some interesting shots overall there is some flavor to Judea in the movie but maybe less about characters and more about smaller occasions like in all Zeffirelli movies the beginning is not as interesting for me as when things get going I have an impression that the beginning is very feminine in some way too unrelated to that in the beginning there is so much talking without blinking and in some special/magical fashion (especially noticable given me loosing remainings of enchantment of religion just recently while looking at religious officials opening a warrior monument that may be controversial) in that &amp;ldquo;surrounding&amp;rdquo; Herod looked as the most understandeable/relateable guy in the beginning but then he goes mad and later previous tranquility is festively contrasted by different rampant sinners and John the Baptist  Then I found out that there are three more parts but I liked the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Il Conformista</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-conformista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 20:44:56 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-conformista/</guid>
      <description>First. Visually interesting without question. I also liked characters there. Of course there is that standard that one expects from classics so I shortly stop praising the movie here.
The movie is bigger than what I can safely analyze. And it probably does not answer the question that leads me to watching it.
There is this word &amp;ldquo;soviet intelligent-sy&amp;rdquo;. It is a negative term for educated but very useful conformists of that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn After Reading</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/burn-after-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 17:21:44 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/burn-after-reading/</guid>
      <description>Initially I thought that &amp;ldquo;extremely funny nonsense&amp;rdquo; describes it all and there is no point to have a post about it.
But then there was another thought that there are multiple stories of different characters and the whole thing is such a mess and is intensive. So that it may require some tools to weave that. Also I have heard that all plots are known already so I bet these directors innovated a bit or used some modern tools to construct that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viridiana</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 20:10:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</guid>
      <description>I did not expect this from a black and white movie somehow but it always finds a way to astonish you.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to add here because it is plain yet very effective. I have strong impression that there is no puzzle that I&amp;rsquo;m so used to like. But the experience by itself does not ask for explanation. It is just that odd and in a way immutable. This way of looking at it seems new to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Charme Discret De La Bourgeoisie</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 22:05:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</guid>
      <description>I saw it before and it left vaguely positive memory.
Overall the picture is light, it is composed from losely tied scenes with some level of humour and absurdity.
I have enjoyed pleasant dialogues and the level of etiquette.
Also humour is low key but can be very fun. Original audio track is a must.
 NOTE: some spoilers ahead
 The movie should be rewatcheable because of how subtle the humour is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Callas Forever</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 21:11:13 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</guid>
      <description>First, I watched it in three sessions as planned.
The beginning predictably left me not excited. The movie provides some words to describe it: &amp;ldquo;too modern&amp;rdquo;. And the word &amp;ldquo;flat&amp;rdquo; came to my mind too. No idea why. I will figure-out one day: is it me or is it how they are made.
At the end of the first third you get to see some development and get intrigued by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Watch</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 05:25:11 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</guid>
      <description>I have noticed that watching in two sessions worked for me well with two Zeffirelli movies (Sparrow, Hamlet).
It can be either due to the way he made movies or due to the way at least my attention works.
Currently I lean to the second option and I also think that this half-watch experience provides similar value as rewatching: more details or connections are being noticed.
I think that it works this way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparrow</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 18:44:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</guid>
      <description>Watched this one in two sessions and the decision worked well. Because about the first session I got the impression that the movie is too much into this suffering thing. And that I&amp;rsquo;m not the right audience for the theme overall. And it surely has those aspects but there are more interesting things and ideas going on.
During the second fresh session I immediately noticed nice directors work. At one point he shot it like it is actually in the space above the planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Notte</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:01:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</guid>
      <description>Just gotta make a post but there is not much I can say&amp;hellip; I decided not to write the post right after watching because I thought the next day I may get some ideas&amp;hellip;
I know this way of structuring stuff is stupid but whatever.
Pros:
 Some nice shots are present Some fun, absurd or just strange scenes are there  Cons:
 pace is not for me messy so called &amp;ldquo;psychological&amp;rdquo; stuff about characters being unhappy and all that does not attract me ugly sounds play from time to time  Notables:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:37:55 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</guid>
      <description>Initially the movie seems simple then I just got to think that it is not what I undestood enough to really write something constructive.
Anyway visually I&amp;rsquo;m just too easy to impress so I liked many &amp;ldquo;shots&amp;rdquo;.
There were also some of these scenes that directors do that take your breath without something explicitly dramatic happening.
I beleive it can have rewatch value but only in some very close-watch analysis mode&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:06:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</guid>
      <description>One notable thing my acquaintance with Antonioni is that how bad initial impression was. First I started watching one movie and just turned it off after having a minute or two watching at something ugly with construction sounds at the background. Now I decided to try another one and you guess what. It throws at you some totally mess of sounds during the initial credits. Then it contrasts it by some piano notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taming of the Shrew</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/taming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:32:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/taming/</guid>
      <description>The one by Zeffirelli. Planned to watch this in two session but got too interested and watched in one.
The first impression is what is called &amp;ldquo;Tube sound&amp;rdquo; in Russia at least. So it is more warm and comfortable quality of picture in this case. After watching two modern space movies previously there is no surprise, but I beleive it is quality of the movie too. It is wild but in more natural way because it is a comedy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brother Sun, Sister Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:19:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</guid>
      <description>I watched it some time ago so I may forget someting that I wanted to say here.
It is exalted. I remember that there are some nice images. As a viewer I did beleive that the guy has a vision. And it was compelling in some way to me.
I remembered very obvious scene when the ceremony when hair being cut is followed by sheep flock with some of them being cut too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:07:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</guid>
      <description>Watched the movie. It seems more balanced than Interstellar. It has both cheesy stuff like males self-sacraficing while looking into females face (Interstellar also has exactly that). But it also has more like that will and action against entropy and even gravity itself.
It has some naked legs Lara Croft action too.
It has some of what can be commonly referred as psychological. Initially Lara :) is being handled like a baby in that sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:40:35 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, one day before the historic Unity22 launch I decided to watch Inception. I remembered that the movie was annoying alot of times but stil gave it a try. So this post is about that experience.
Positives I&amp;rsquo;ll start with positives to not be too harsh.
The plot seems to be more interesting that I remembered initially. There were a couple of cool visuals, some nice scenes overall or even I appreciated how certain scenes were directed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea with Mussolini</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 13:21:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</guid>
      <description>The movie is like a story with different aspects to it. It has a bit of everything from nice views to light comedy and interesting people in odd situations. But then it turned to be a small puzzle that I got solved here while writing the post.
One thing I got to remember are how imposing Mussolini&amp;rsquo;s table is. Another thing is how nicely and lightly trashy art is being advertised in one scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blowup</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</guid>
      <description>My first movie of the director. I have seen some time ago and now decided to give a try to works of Antonioni overall. I put there thoughts I got from it.
Scenes: In the beginning credits are shown in an interesting way you kind of see somethnig by through letters but you only see the gist. The movie starts with fun-car, and then death-camp-looking corridor - contrast from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L Innocente</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:37:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t use names here because they does not matter. It is not a movie for rewatching for me. I feel that that &amp;ldquo;dark freedom&amp;rdquo; mixed with good looks is a bit repulsive. One the other hand it still takes it&amp;rsquo;s own place. With it&amp;rsquo;s own confused ugliness in a nice shaped environment. But still roles do not deserve names from my point of view. No idea why.
TLDR: Crazy miscommunication between genders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senso</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 08:52:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful aesthetics. Not to say about views of Venice and Italy. Both strong feelings and something different also.
My version of the movie was missing Livia money explanation scene :). The actress plays very well if you ask me. But she convincingly plays something very different. So I can not imagine that scene and would like to see that!
There is a class difference that I see in different movies. Also there is blindness that is imposed on Livia by her nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lo Straniero / The Stranger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 14:50:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: I have found out that it is by a novel by Camus so I bet this stuff is already analysed well. But I write my thoughts on the movie for myself partially to remember it better and partially to analyze it better in the process of writing/watching. Also writing stuff is not a bad idea by itself.
 Due to me confusing this movie with another I considered comments on the internet odd so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t excited to start watching it and delayed this movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ossessione</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 20:20:15 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</guid>
      <description>Watched Obsession by Visconti. I did it in two sessions and the movie is divided in two parts by itself also.
Spoilers ahead of course. I write stuf in two sessions so I may forgot something.
Lightning I like that at the time movies were made with lightning being used at the maximal capacity. You see it being used remarkably through the movie (from mine beginner-enthusiast point of view).
There are different small scenes that I noticed visually even if I don&amp;rsquo;t remember dialogs: only the theme or direction plus some visual clues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandra | Vaghe stelle dell&#39;Orsa</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 18:27:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</guid>
      <description>Context I decided to return to quality movies after having a break from wathing anything. And not having time organized resulted in me watching the movie in multiple sessins.
Thoughts It was always visually interesting experience for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect black and white movies being such rich medium. Also all scenes with piano being played on camera I watched twice for sure.
I beleive there is a rewatch value of the movie overall even though it is not that complex in the story as I see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visconti</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:06:32 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching different Visconti movies these days for the first time.
I decided to have some stuff written. Possibly not very important one but I feel like writing stuff can have some value by itself. Maybe because the writing itself can help me to think and produce some analysis now or even if I will want to add something later.
Also I can&amp;rsquo;t be certain if I keep this with or without spoilers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death in Venice</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:06:53 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</guid>
      <description>Analysis Meta Being watching Visconti for the first time recently.
Decided to record a post on this one because it is more than it seems in many ways.
I plan to have this one without spoilers because I like myself to find things in movies and there is no value in being explicit potentially ruining that for somebody.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the book. I have checked some comments on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stelling&#43;</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:46:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</guid>
      <description>Non-Stelling First I watched The Godfather, a couple of Nolan movies, Coffee and Cigarettes.
Concerning The Godfather I also watched a comentary and analysis which also adds weight and value to the understanding of how the movie made.
Concerning Nolan. I first thought that he is getting old with his Tenet having stamps and otherwise annoying scenes. Even though I liked ideas and realization and the key scenes of course are my kind of content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
