<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movies on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movies on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:04:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Shining</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-shining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:04:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-shining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;mist&#34;&gt;Mist&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t recall my first experience of the movie.&#xA;So there is this interesting state when you got some cinema literacy and&#xA;may have the illusion that you can&amp;rsquo;t see it with fresh eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maybe the whole remote Hotel theme invokes that feeling that there&#xA;are experiences remote in the past that you can&amp;rsquo;t even recall, not to say about making sense of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;got-scared-off&#34;&gt;Got scared off&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I watched the movie in a headset.&#xA;I generally control fear response by having controlled volume and being analytical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinatown</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/chinatown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 14:06:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/chinatown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-impression&#34;&gt;First impression&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quality movie with meditative texture.&#xA;It gives some shallow visual entertainment in the process.&#xA;So it makes the impression of being mostly shallow too.&#xA;And there is not much motivation to rewatch it by itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;second-layer&#34;&gt;Second layer&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve heard it is a way deeper movie, I gave some scenes another look.&#xA;And yes, there is more to it, so depth is there, and it is up for rewatch at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raging Bull</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/raging-bull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/raging-bull/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think there was general context of hearing how this was one of the movies notably influenced by Powell and Pressburger cinema.&#xA;The movie&amp;rsquo;s title sequence by itself confirms that art-cinema aspect being there.&#xA;And actually it confirms the reference, if one wants to see it from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watching it from that perspective ain&amp;rsquo;t satisaction guaranteed kind of entertainment, but it actually gave me some enjoyable parallels.&#xA;And that development and difference compared to the reference tool used is what enriches overall cinema experience by structuring it more.&#xA;Also it gave some of own picture&amp;rsquo;s language that could be missed without that kind of attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Desert of the Tartars</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-desert-of-the-tartars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 06:47:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-desert-of-the-tartars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the movie and then read the book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My impression is that the book is more introspective, personal and imaginative, while the movie has more of the class component and is on the real side, which has its own depth that I enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie is consistently visual.&#xA;But the book features outstanding stones scene that I appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also the book had this effect that movie would not have.&#xA;It made me to recall some of old memories about conscript military service.&#xA;It was as remote location as one can get excluding locations considered remote for harsh climate conditions.&#xA;The place also was with ruins here and there because of earthquakes years before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made in England: the Films of Powell and Pressburger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As any good film this documentary addresses different audiences&amp;rsquo; interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It could be seen as an overview and an introduction to the cinema of Powel and Pressburger also branded The Archers.&#xA;I like how creative paths of that collaboration and M. Scorsese are interwoven in different ways.&#xA;So, it can be seen as double documentary to some extent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not a documentary in any dull sense because the subject cinema is so creative, expressive and as strong or as subtle as one allows it to be.&#xA;In 2023 BFI called the event celebrating the artists &amp;ldquo;Cinema Unbound&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2001: A Space Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:30:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/2001-a-space-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The simpler/more-explicit movie so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to stick to just first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I expected the movie to be about cardinal topic.&#xA;The topic is human state and experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;spoilers-if-you-like&#34;&gt;Spoilers if you like&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The topic is shown from two angles overimposed: intelligence and reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The black rectangular prism means evolution crossing some limit.&#xA;All four key appearances signify something fundamental to human experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First: &amp;ldquo;monkeys&amp;rdquo; get natural intelligence evolved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second: superficially - artificial intelligence gets discovered, but I&amp;rsquo;d say there is more to that AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third: is experience of body generation complexity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fourth: is limit of unacheivable by every previous generation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie feels very humane at certain moments dispite it being not the most cozy watch.&#xA;Understanding the whole thing makes it a comedy too.&#xA;This makes for an interesting depth in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the Face</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a breaking of the fourth wall element in theater/cinema.&#xA;I recall the name only after I start to see significance of such tools.&#xA;For example, in Killer&amp;rsquo;s of the Flower Moon, there are at least two sneaky breakings of the fourth wall&#xA;and one obvious one at the end.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d say, even if sneaky, they signify key moments to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For whatever questionable reason, I watched Perfect Days by Wim Wenders too recently.&#xA;Somehow, the director, even if the he has great work, tends to be mentioned by Russian speaking people who signal sophistication.&#xA;And I&amp;rsquo;m fine if somebody references, at least after watching it, if the reference is good.&#xA;But in that case, the referencer probably asked chat-gpt and got hallucinated and confused mix of stuff.&#xA;So it was the worst possible reference, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to think about that.&#xA;(BTW: I use chat-gpt to put commas around; hopefully, that does not make my references bad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killers of the Flower Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:56:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;before&#34;&gt;Before&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What got my attention to the movie is unexpected change on one channel.&#xA;The channel had comments turned off and occasionally different art was posted there.&#xA;Then there appeared somewhat simplistic yet dissonant review of the movie and comments went turned on.&#xA;I knew that M. Scorsese looks into ethnical differences and criminal characters and groups.&#xA;I think I guessed right at the time what moved the channel&amp;rsquo;s author.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matter of Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hypnotic start and common but strange finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes things not said or not shown are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here I see ideas about thunderbolt, neuron growth, ladder, and &amp;ldquo;flight from Berlin&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Also script should have some ideas that did not make it into the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is propaganda angle to it which is fine by me. I think it is still strong even if the idea of Anglo-American cooperation in the new world is ignored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Narcissus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a type of lucid Disney movie crossing into a horror film. The earliest erotic movie. Melodrama about nuns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoilers may lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;team&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In director&amp;rsquo;s commentary M. Powell mentions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;high quality of the team and art department&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cases of intrinsic match of actors to roles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;directors role of believing in the project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how the team kind of lived through the movie (without big picture possibly?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And this final point probably assumes a degree of improvisation on actors part in the process&#xA;and also a degree of freedom during the editing part.&#xA;Although I have information about the director being very exacting.&#xA;So I have no idea really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes Wide Shut</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:45:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eyes-wide-shut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of this director and I recall some things to be interesting&#xA;I otherwise avoided watching his work because the name seemed too popular.&#xA;Checked this one for a random reason.&#xA;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about the choice for the first half maybe.&#xA;But then the director delivered technically.&#xA;And then I got to see the conception that is brilliant too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Delivered in colorful and crinkling packaging to distract the viewer;&#xA;simultaneously Christmas and Halloween joke played right on the viewer;&#xA;yet also having a personal down to earth snapshot of not obvious family business management at one point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Himmel über Berlin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/der-himmel-uber-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 21:11:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/der-himmel-uber-berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though the pace of the movie may be not too fast and given certain melancholy and lots of internal monologues there.&#xA;After watching the movie it actually left positive if not optimistic and very humane impression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the 10-th minute there is explicit visual play with reflected lights.&#xA;And this sets the standard and expectation.&#xA;So the viewer is practically encouraged to analyze other visuals used.&#xA;But also that play by itself may worth a rewatch or two after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Dolce Vita</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-dolce-vita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 08:00:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-dolce-vita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rich movie, unforgettable images&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of echoes inside&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suns and moons, ladders and crosses and rain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watching and thinking about movies like that leaves echoes in you and enhance perception of reality for some time.&#xA;Again as in Mariken van Nieumeghen there was this effect when invisibles, things not shown, make you seek them and ultimately to find in some form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scenes and images may be viewed from different angles and the viewer is free to choose which way they go with the movie.&#xA;The more patched nature of the movie may relax constrains on interpretation of scenes to some extent.&#xA;The movie even has abstract poetry read at some point, what highlights and invites ambiguity.&#xA;Level of details and different themes touched makes for a rich mix and questions posed of different level of visibility anchor viewer to pay attention.&#xA;Echoes in the movie helps you compose the picture in non-linear way for even richer composition to go beyond superficial limits of the medium.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insomnia</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/insomnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 15:18:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/insomnia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have seen both Insomnias - first the one by Nolan and then the one by Skjoldbjærg.&#xA;I wanted to record something on this so Nolan goes first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First I recognized some Twin Peaks atmosphere to it.&#xA;Then also Nolan very explicitly plays with one straightforward idea and you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it.&#xA;This adds entertainment value all over the movie however slow it seems to be.&#xA;Interestingly it makes some scenes way more memorable because you have more structure to them.&#xA;Then surely given unusual state of affairs of roles Al Pacino offers another entertaining piece of the picture.&#xA;Also I think innate visual fabric of the movie may suggest some further ideas but it is as if some frame or composition is not there to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversation Piece</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/conversation-piece/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 20:54:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/conversation-piece/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched the piece again and saw some of it&amp;rsquo;s riches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most obvious, simple yet exceptional scene that shows what can be called &amp;ldquo;unveiling&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Enjoyable echo to Vaghe stelle dell&amp;rsquo;Orsa right there.&#xA;But the scene is crisp clear even by itself in the context of one movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secondly there are scenes before and after it that have some non-obvious play too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not to say that I believe there is a mini-ghost in the movie too and I don&amp;rsquo;t know why yet.&#xA;Is it another echo? But this one is subtle enough to puzzle you whether it is there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loading</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 15:31:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After getting excited by New York Stories.&#xA;I thought a bit about whether co-creation in form of potentially loading posts about movies with my at times far reaching interpretations or implications is the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I say it can&amp;rsquo;t be other way.&#xA;Authentic and entertaining go together in my mind.&#xA;So the genre of this personal blog should be something around: random observations and imaginations well-mixed in a skull shaped bowl and sprinkled with grammar errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Stories</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 09:16:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Talking about the first segment here.&#xA;Awesome and controversial piece.&#xA;Watching this only one time is not getting the value.&#xA;And general context of watching should be different too so I&amp;#39;d recommend arbitrary time gap between sessions.&#xA;Also spoilers here may spoil the second watch too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The first segment of New York Stories is by Martin Scorsese.&#xA;I watched the segment twice with some delay and wrote this later still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Das Boot</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 18:39:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-boot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eyes of war&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also about human state in general&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Religious theme at one point sounds almost as if they are not sure if God sees them underwater&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heroism, leadership, team dynamics, failure of administration: absurdity and sabotage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notably silent communication and how everybody understands and predicts others&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Impressive opening sequence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emilie Muller</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/emilie-muller/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 16:44:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/emilie-muller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;spoilers-and-all&#34;&gt;Spoilers and all&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how to dominate audition without dominating it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how to sell oneself without selling oneself&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how fools are given once in a lifetime random opportunity and how they loose it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;assuming that black and white is used to invoke some spirit of old stars&#xA;and this is contrasted to this gray whatever that fails to catch one&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;enjoyable very direct format&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Les Miserables</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/les-miserables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 09:28:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/les-miserables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the outside it is a music box that is visually tasty and theatrical.&#xA;When you open it you are there for multitude of melodies of crying among other serious and humorous lines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may make an impression of some femininity aspect&#xA;or certain serious non-seriousness, naivete and oversimplification/cliche-even&#xA;or even offensive to somebody&amp;rsquo;s perception of normal and mirror-neurons abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Offended crowd is not the one worth listening to&#xA;but still perception of such toys may need the right mindset that they don&amp;rsquo;t possess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genre Change</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 08:24:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/genre-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;path&#34;&gt;Path&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Movie-wise personally the 2022 was marked by the sign of genre change.&#xA;It has started with the Witch Burned Alive enchanting piece.&#xA;It progressed into the dark-aesthetics and contrasting world of Mariken van Nieumeghen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I hit the inverse apex of anti-aesthetics in re-watching some old clip on some odd verses by Epifancev.&#xA;Given new tools this was readable and superficial/catchy but with presence of relatively sophisticated technology.&#xA;Surely there can be different readings but I got one slice that makes experience easy and does not cause any kind of stackoverflows while having enough consistency and enough new learnings.&#xA;Given me being outsider to these crafts I got impressed by the experience technology used there.&#xA;Both in verses and the video on top of them.&#xA;This time the experience was without the &amp;ldquo;noise in torn-out ears without head&amp;rdquo; in the process&#xA;and this more professional-like clear-minded look produces no less impression.&#xA;Although I still visibly have a prejudice against this approach maybe because it is finite, maybe because it implies some level of organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mariken van Nieumeghen</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mariken-van-nieumeghen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 11:18:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mariken-van-nieumeghen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep and raw fish of a picture with strokes of celestial.&#xA;May be dark at times and thus not for any audience and mood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The director is a master of visual language.&#xA;This is why the movie is rewatchable and rich.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just mention one scene.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The director talks straight: right above a door that Mariken enters he puts an exclamation mark with light and shadows.&#xA;After that you see details that are necessary but I&amp;rsquo;ll skip them to not elaborate further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memento</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 05:17:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/memento/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I ended-up watching some movies recently.&#xA;One of them ended-up being Memento.&#xA;Movies were good but I had no idea for a post until yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is that things that are not expressed may end-up being non-existing in the first place.&#xA;This may not be an idea behind the movie but this is the idea behind the post in its way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;movie&#34;&gt;Movie&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie is an interesting patchwork of scenes that go in reverse chronological order.&#xA;Each has its own references mostly in regard to questions of memory and communication.&#xA;I found topic of drugs abuse and isolation being represented too but more indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planet Parade</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/planet-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 20:22:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/planet-parade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good soviet movie about middle-aged males gathering for a trip.&#xA;The viewer has lots of moments of reflection on deep matters of existence and life.&#xA;Offering nostalgia and sharpened sense of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie was mentioned on Arestovich&amp;rsquo;s program twice AFAIK.&#xA;So that added it to my list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally after having listened to some classics it is especially hard to&#xA;get me interesting in a soviet movie with military theme.&#xA;But this one was chosen and it got my attention from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeping Tom</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 15:36:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert and all that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I watched Peeping Tom a couple of weeks ago.&#xA;It is now or never I should write-down what I thought about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points&#34;&gt;Key points&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;many things at once is how I see it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the idea that fear is the scariest thing is liberating&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;lots of visual language, some just makes you puzzled, some is obvious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it succeeded at confusing me at points surely&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;effect: not scared but puzzled&#xA;(which is good, scaredness would inhibit analysis)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;high contrast movie: hilarious/odd/interesting scenes,&#xA;different personalities,&#xA;direct contrast and directors tools can be seen or&#xA;you just feel their presence even if not sure what exactly is there;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;fearless desensitized vs fearless normal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;magic camera aspect I have not resolved - some positive vision probably&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;topic of desensitization by the industry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;enjoyed accents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality&#34;&gt;Quality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;all this baits you in for partial-rewatch even though&#xA;there is some empuzzlement and repulsion present as a general feeling&#xA;but the director did his work&#xA;by quality in all regards to cover for the theme effect;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the movie is like a shopping stall of goods about directing things&#xA;and producing effects, &amp;ldquo;things perceptable and the general level&#xA;is not distracting your from products&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;so there should be rewatch value from that for sure;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is not at all an ADHD fast-paced salad&#xA;so you have your time to think about stuff,&#xA;I liked that for sure,&#xA;yet it leaves an impresson of being filled with quality material;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;exceprts&#34;&gt;Exceprts&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That &amp;ldquo;he is the director&amp;rdquo; I understood it (but not at that moment)&#xA;as both:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Lights</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/city-lights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:15:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/city-lights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-context&#34;&gt;Some Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Got the bats flu the most recent stemm as it seems.&#xA;Charlie Chaplin was on my list to check - out.&#xA;So the opportunity to do that was realized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also Charlie Chaplin is such a phenomenon.&#xA;And there is this familiarity to his character that you develop.&#xA;So it feels totally ok to just use Charlie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;city-lights&#34;&gt;City Lights&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Touching story. Wery well played. Enjoyed the comedy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Charlie had his own independent studio at the time of shooting.&#xA;And compared to the earliest short silent comedy that I have had an opportunity to check.&#xA;This definetly looks like more serios work.&#xA;Surely you get what is expected - extremely comical scenes.&#xA;And you get more variability because of length.&#xA;But you also get the main plot that makes it a real movie.&#xA;And there is something more I believe.&#xA;Maybe it is that you can alter the speed of the show&#xA;when you are not constrained by the short format.&#xA;And Charlie uses that option to have scenes of different pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;oro Di Napoli</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loro-di-napoli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 20:58:13 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/loro-di-napoli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not the first time I see this.&#xA;But I like it when I see how tools of craftsman are being used.&#xA;It makes things more understandable and more like communication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I liked how director emphasises certain places.&#xA;That anchor then can reappear in memory later while adding to the experience.&#xA;Or even offering small rewatch opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also I liked how in one episode some theme from the preceeding one was confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le Streghe (Visconti part)</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/le-streghe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 20:16:51 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/le-streghe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoilers Land&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie has multiple parts.&#xA;I accidentially started watching the one by Visconti that I had already seen at that point and got sucked-in.&#xA;And then to write more gave another look.&#xA;And then I could not resisit another look&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The setting is in the Alps.&#xA;Alot of botanical framed pictures everywhere represent the topic on the walls.&#xA;Lack of acquaintance with arts limits the viewer at different points&amp;hellip;&#xA;Red color is favored there.&#xA;Some shots are very likeable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Il Giovane Toscanini</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-giovane-toscanini/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 11:08:48 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-giovane-toscanini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are always visuals that I enjoy in Zeffirelli movies and I think it is just my taste being very simple in a way.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m not at the point where I can be specific about visual styles of directors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plot offers a streak of victories to the protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First at La Scala when he gets a better opportinity where he is more valued;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second when he revives the diva;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third when he again exchanges the conventional success for the soulmate and a new undertaking;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And then becomes a conductor too, saving and even altering the performance, making it feel more like a historic event;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think one theme that goes through the movie is how new generation finds and takes it&amp;rsquo;s place.&#xA;The name suggests that too. Maybe I should just read the list of all plots finally so I don&amp;rsquo;t need to analyze but maybe something is lost then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simon of Desert</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 13:02:48 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/simon-of-desert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched alot of stuff in 2021 that I&amp;rsquo;d like to write something about just to see how it goes.&#xA;But there should be a starting point somewhere and the most recent movie is the subject of the post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie is short so the post should follow the shape of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I have seen is lots of patches with with some light humour everywhere in between.&#xA;Patches are different and that may be confusing because it looks like there are serious topics interwoven.&#xA;But in the end humour is the unifying line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blues</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:52:57 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking into Blues and got this series produced by Scorsese.&#xA;I liked Vinyl series so checking this too sounded like a good idea.&#xA;I watch it in the order of my own relevance/preference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The part by Clint Eastwood got me interested from some unexpected angle.&#xA;Most of the time music itself did not attract me.&#xA;And that got me interested even more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly he tried to capture some of that atmosphere so brought those characters to convey it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Otto E Mezzo</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/otto-e-mezzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 12:27:38 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/otto-e-mezzo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see quality from the start.&#xA;A movie about life and play that says it for itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the director tools point of view I have noticed that the director conveys some things before actualy revealing them.&#xA;So there is a rewatch value added just by that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also some scenes are spectacular for unknown reasons - this must have been studied well already.&#xA;But that I think is not what plain rewatch helps with. Only if it is timed well after other high quality content to compare to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pagliacci</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/pagliacci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 18:26:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/pagliacci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched this one without knowledge of libretto and without understanding of language and that was not the best idea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visually and overall I&amp;rsquo;m attracted to the topic of such strange wandering performers.&#xA;But as very often happens - you get the shape but there is something else joined to it and you don&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the thing you expected initially.&#xA;So one may think that the first thing was there just to&#xA;create an illusion of something new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cavalleria Rusticana</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cavalleria-rusticana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 21:31:12 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cavalleria-rusticana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched it without subtitles or anything.&#xA;Actually didn&amp;rsquo;t even know the libretto and the name of what I was watching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally tragedy is not the genre I watch or even understand.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m repulced by the ending of Lakme for example.&#xA;Some things should not be played because they can&amp;rsquo;t be played truthfully I believe.&#xA;But probably I&amp;rsquo;m getting to be more open minded about the genre.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time I found myself being very empathetic to Elena Obrazcova so I believe she played well.&#xA;Maybe because there was no speech and I tried to understand things so I payed more attention.&#xA;Also since I was free from verbal processing I watched from the point of a director in a way.&#xA;I payed more attention to gestures and their meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Joe Black</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/meet-joe-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 21:05:23 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/meet-joe-black/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You see the good quality there.&#xA;There is class I believe too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One can say that the play is very detailed. Even this that is not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to capture but it is definetly visible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The topic touched is often serious so to move to another scene the director has small humorous scenes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall pace may be slow and the length is longish.&#xA;At some points you may think: &amp;ldquo;What kind of dialogs are these?&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;You already know what is being said but they still dictate own pace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus of Nazareth (upd: final episode)</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jesus-of-nazareth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:30:19 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jesus-of-nazareth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE: spoils may lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I watched only the first part of fourth at this point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;like I guess all Zeffirelli movies this one has beautiful nature shots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;also some interesting shots overall&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there is some flavor to Judea in the movie but maybe less about characters and more about smaller occasions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;like in all Zeffirelli movies the beginning is not as interesting for me as when things get going&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I have an impression that the beginning is very feminine in some way too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;unrelated to that in the beginning there is so much talking without blinking and in some special/magical fashion (especially noticable given me loosing remainings of enchantment of religion just recently while looking at religious officials opening a warrior monument that may be controversial)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;in that &amp;ldquo;surrounding&amp;rdquo; Herod looked as the most understandeable/relateable guy in the beginning but then he goes mad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;and later previous tranquility is festively contrasted by different rampant sinners and John the Baptist&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I found out that there are three more parts but I liked the idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Il Conformista</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-conformista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 20:44:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/il-conformista/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First. Visually interesting without question.&#xA;I also liked characters there.&#xA;Of course there is that standard that one expects from classics so I shortly stop praising the movie here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie is bigger than what I can safely analyze.&#xA;And it probably does not answer the question that leads me to watching it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is this word &amp;ldquo;soviet intelligent-sy&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;It is a negative term for educated but very useful conformists of that time.&#xA;And I hear this from time to time that conformists are intelligent because it is expedient thing to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burn After Reading</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/burn-after-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 17:21:44 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/burn-after-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially I thought that &amp;ldquo;extremely funny nonsense&amp;rdquo; describes it all and there is no point to have a post about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But then there was another thought that there are multiple stories of different characters and the whole thing is such a mess and is intensive.&#xA;So that it may require some tools to weave that.&#xA;Also I have heard that all plots are known already so I bet these directors innovated a bit or used some modern tools to construct that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viridiana</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 20:10:41 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/viridiana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did not expect this from a black and white movie somehow&#xA;but it always finds a way to astonish you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to add here because it is plain yet very effective.&#xA;I have strong impression that there is no puzzle that I&amp;rsquo;m so used to like.&#xA;But the experience by itself does not ask for explanation.&#xA;It is just that odd and in a way immutable.&#xA;This way of looking at it seems new to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Charme Discret De La Bourgeoisie</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 22:05:28 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-charme-discret-de-la-bourgeoisie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw it before and it left vaguely positive memory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall the picture is light, it is composed from losely tied scenes with some level of humour and absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have enjoyed pleasant dialogues and the level of etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also humour is low key but can be very fun. Original audio track is a must.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: some spoilers ahead&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie should be rewatcheable because of how subtle the humour is.&#xA;One random phrase can be just so fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Callas Forever</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 21:11:13 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/callas-forever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I watched it in three sessions as planned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beginning predictably left me not excited.&#xA;The movie provides some words to describe it: &amp;ldquo;too modern&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;And the word &amp;ldquo;flat&amp;rdquo; came to my mind too.&#xA;No idea why.&#xA;I will figure-out one day: is it me or is it how they are made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first third you get to see some &lt;strong&gt;development&lt;/strong&gt; and get intrigued by it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half Watch</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 05:25:11 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/half-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that watching in two sessions worked for me well with two Zeffirelli movies (Sparrow, Hamlet).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It can be either due to the way he made movies or due to the way at least my attention works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently I lean to the second option and I also think that this half-watch experience provides&#xA;similar value as rewatching: more details or connections are being noticed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think that it works this way:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparrow</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 18:44:02 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sparrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched this one in two sessions and the decision worked well.&#xA;Because about the first session I got the impression that the movie is too much into this suffering thing.&#xA;And that I&amp;rsquo;m not the right audience for the theme overall.&#xA;And it surely has those aspects but there are more interesting things and ideas going on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the second fresh session I immediately noticed nice directors work.&#xA;At one point he shot it like it is actually in the space above the planet. Very cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Notte</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 20:01:48 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/la-notte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just gotta make a post but there is not much I can say&amp;hellip;&#xA;I decided not to write the post right after watching because I thought the next day I may get some ideas&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know this way of structuring stuff is stupid but whatever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some nice shots are present&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some fun, absurd or just strange scenes are there&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pace is not for me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;messy so called &amp;ldquo;psychological&amp;rdquo; stuff about characters&#xA;being unhappy and all that does not attract me&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ugly sounds play from time to time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notables:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:37:55 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially the movie seems simple then I just got to think that it is not what I undestood enough to really write something constructive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway visually I&amp;rsquo;m just too easy to impress so I liked many &amp;ldquo;shots&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were also some of these scenes that directors do that take your breath without something explicitly dramatic happening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I beleive it can have rewatch value but only in some very close-watch analysis mode&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:06:25 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/eclipse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One notable thing my acquaintance with Antonioni is that how bad initial impression was.&#xA;First I started watching one movie and just turned it off after having a minute or two watching at something ugly with construction sounds at the background.&#xA;Now I decided to try another one and you guess what.&#xA;It throws at you some totally mess of sounds during the initial credits.&#xA;Then it contrasts it by some piano notes.&#xA;But anyway I have no idea what to think about that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Taming of the Shrew</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/taming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:32:28 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/taming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one by Zeffirelli.&#xA;Planned to watch this in two session but got too interested and watched in one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first impression is what is called &amp;ldquo;Tube sound&amp;rdquo; in Russia at least.&#xA;So it is more warm and comfortable quality of picture in this case.&#xA;After watching two modern space movies previously there is no surprise, but I beleive&#xA;it is quality of the movie too.&#xA;It is wild but in more natural way because it is a comedy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brother Sun, Sister Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:19:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched it some time ago so I may forget someting that I wanted to say here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is exalted. I remember that there are some nice images.&#xA;As a viewer I did beleive that the guy has a vision.&#xA;And it was compelling in some way to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I remembered very obvious scene when the ceremony when hair being cut is followed by sheep flock with some of them being cut too.&#xA;So the director says that the beauty and more superficial/temporal is there to be put to use and reaped somehow.&#xA;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really understand the idea deep but the sequence was too obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gravity</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:07:26 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched the movie.&#xA;It seems more balanced than Interstellar.&#xA;It has both cheesy stuff like males self-sacraficing while looking into females face (Interstellar also has exactly that).&#xA;But it also has more like that will and action against entropy and even gravity itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has some naked legs Lara Croft action too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has some of what can be commonly referred as psychological.&#xA;Initially Lara :) is being handled like a baby in that sense.&#xA;But later she does redefines herself against memory and negative experience in a positive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:40:35 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, one day before the historic Unity22 launch I decided to watch Inception.&#xA;I remembered that the movie was annoying alot of times but stil gave it a try.&#xA;So this post is about that experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;positives&#34;&gt;Positives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll start with positives to not be too harsh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plot seems to be more interesting that I remembered initially.&#xA;There were a couple of cool visuals, some nice scenes overall or even I appreciated how certain scenes were directed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tea with Mussolini</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 13:21:49 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The movie is like a story with different aspects to it.&#xA;It has a bit of everything from nice views to light comedy and interesting people in odd situations.&#xA;But then it turned to be a small puzzle that I got solved here while writing the post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing I got to remember are how imposing Mussolini&amp;rsquo;s table is.&#xA;Another thing is how nicely and lightly trashy art is being advertised in one scene.&#xA;And in such a way that I started to think how it should be looked at to see stuff this way&amp;hellip;&#xA;I even came-up with an idea about that but then I got more sober view on the scene in the context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blowup</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:18 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first movie of the director.&#xA;I have seen some time ago and now decided to give a try to works of Antonioni overall.&#xA;I put there thoughts I got from it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scenes:&#xA;In the beginning credits are shown in an interesting way&#xA;you kind of see somethnig by through letters but you only see the gist.&#xA;The movie starts with fun-car, and then death-camp-looking corridor - contrast from the start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L Innocente</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:37:03 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t use names here because they does not matter.&#xA;It is not a movie for rewatching for me.&#xA;I feel that that &amp;ldquo;dark freedom&amp;rdquo; mixed with good looks is a bit repulsive.&#xA;One the other hand it still takes it&amp;rsquo;s own place.&#xA;With it&amp;rsquo;s own confused ugliness in a nice shaped environment.&#xA;But still roles do not deserve names from my point of view.&#xA;No idea why.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TLDR: Crazy miscommunication between genders. A female makes a poor choice of the husband. Then gets his attention by having somebody on a side with unintended consequences. Then basically tells him to solve the problem while not understandnig it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senso</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 08:52:25 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beautiful aesthetics.&#xA;Not to say about views of Venice and Italy.&#xA;Both strong feelings and something different also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My version of the movie was missing Livia money explanation scene :).&#xA;The actress plays very well if you ask me. But she convincingly plays something very different.&#xA;So I can not imagine that scene and would like to see that!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a class difference that I see in different movies.&#xA;Also there is blindness that is imposed on Livia by her nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lo Straniero / The Stranger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 14:50:02 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTE: I have found out that it is by a novel by Camus so I bet this stuff is already analysed well.&#xA;But I write my thoughts on the movie for myself partially to remember it better and partially&#xA;to analyze it better in the process of writing/watching.&#xA;Also writing stuff is not a bad idea by itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to me confusing this movie with another I considered comments on the internet odd so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t excited to start watching it and delayed this movie.&#xA;But actually it was a good movie for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ossessione</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 20:20:15 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched Obsession by Visconti.&#xA;I did it in two sessions and the movie is divided in two parts by itself also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoilers ahead of course.&#xA;I write stuf in two sessions so I may forgot something.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;lightning&#34;&gt;Lightning&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like that at the time movies were made with lightning being used at the maximal capacity.&#xA;You see it being used remarkably through the movie (from mine beginner-enthusiast point of view).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are different small scenes that I noticed visually even if I don&amp;rsquo;t remember dialogs: only the theme or direction plus some visual clues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sandra | Vaghe stelle dell&#39;Orsa</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 18:27:41 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to return to quality movies after having a break from wathing anything.&#xA;And not having time organized resulted in me watching the movie in multiple sessins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was always visually interesting experience for me.&#xA;I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect black and white movies being such rich medium.&#xA;Also all scenes with piano being played on camera I watched twice for sure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I beleive there is a rewatch value of the movie overall even though it is not that complex in the story as I see it.&#xA;There are definetly smaller scenes that need another look to understand thinking of characters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visconti</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:06:32 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching different Visconti movies these days for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to have some stuff written.&#xA;Possibly not very important one but I feel like writing stuff can have some value by itself.&#xA;Maybe because the writing itself can help me to think and produce some analysis now or even if I will want to add something later.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also I can&amp;rsquo;t be certain if I keep this with or without spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death in Venice</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:06:53 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;analysis&#34;&gt;Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;Meta&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being watching Visconti for the first time recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decided to record a post on this one because it is more than it seems in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I plan to have this one without spoilers because I like myself to find things in movies&#xA;and there is no value in being explicit potentially ruining that for somebody.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the book.&#xA;I have checked some comments on the internet.&#xA;And I assume the movie is better than the book given how Visconti uses his visual space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stelling&#43;</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:46:23 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-stelling&#34;&gt;Non-Stelling&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First I watched The Godfather, a couple of Nolan movies, Coffee and Cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concerning The Godfather I also watched a comentary and analysis which also adds weight and value to the understanding of how the movie made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concerning Nolan.&#xA;I first thought that he is getting old with his Tenet having stamps and otherwise annoying scenes.&#xA;Even though I liked ideas and realization and the key scenes of course are my kind of content.&#xA;Then I went for Inception to have a comparsion and that annoyance was still there (and appreciation of the good content) so it is not Nolan&#xA;who is getting older :).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
