<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haidt on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/haidt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Haidt on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 19:58:51 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/haidt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Righteous Mind</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-righteous-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 19:58:51 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-righteous-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Found-out that scribd has some good stuff that I wanted to check like this title.&#xA;So I got over first three chapters in audio format.&#xA;Looking at how it goes I would switch to the short version in this case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat while listening to it because the author does alot of stuff in the beginning for sure. I think consciously but  who knows;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Even though narrated by the author the experience is very copy-paste/so-conventional from the execution point of view. No idea why;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also the author talks like he talks to children. I know that he is a professor. I&amp;rsquo;m curious if he gives lectures and it is a thing to talk like that in education there. Also he is a professor of psychology - maybe that has specifics;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also the premise that author argues in the first three chapters is that reason just follows intuition and author actually is guided by that idea in how he presents the argument. So that childish aspect is very obvious;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The second chapter ends in apotheosis of nonsense (I hope) with the promise to be reasonable in the next chapter. It continues where it stopped;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One negative thing with the approach to &amp;ldquo;manipulate&amp;rdquo; reader first is that the author primes some readers to distrust from the start which is a fun way to start;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also the guy could teach a monkey with his premise because he repeats it so often that it feels like you are reading Allen Carr again;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Makes you think that nonsensical packaging these days is like some funny excess clothes back in a day.&#xA;But actually the right thing to do is to go straight after the relevant papers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
