<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whatever on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/whatever/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whatever on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:59:37 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/whatever/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avocaat Party</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/avocaat-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 18:59:37 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/avocaat-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sowcow.github.io/blog/avocaat-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jack avaits&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sowcow.github.io/blog/avocaat-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Grady got&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sowcow.github.io/blog/avocaat-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jack high&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sowcow.github.io/blog/avocaat-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Grady comment&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-got-here&#34;&gt;How I got here&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got here by trying to break away from watching the movie.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The movie always gratifies me intellectually when I rewatch it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So I get hooked on it periodically, find a way to quit, then relapse.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Currently, my movieholic log looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My first quitting attempt was a cognitive solution: I explained the conception to myself from the director’s perspective and not from the events inside the movie. To forget/dilute The Shining, I started watching more different movies, mostly horror.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The second time, after relapsing, I did a creative way of exiting: first, I found an actual exit point for the viewer in the movie (it’s quite elaborate), then I also arranged the Snakes and Ladders post that has evolved in meaning for me since then. Then, later, I quit watching anything.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;My current attempt is a pre-cognitive mechanism: by simply solving the disgust layer in the movie, I’d get repelled. Instead, it got humorous, and I’m happy with in even more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;traumatic-partying&#34;&gt;Traumatic partying&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie, by itself, is like a trauma if viewed seriously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demoralization by Example</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/demoralization-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 09:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/demoralization-by-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are different meanings of demoralization that I&amp;rsquo;m aware of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bezmenov meant total war by exporting ideologies that wipe-out moral reference-points and&#xA;cause fracturing and internal conflict.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arestovich was talking about waves-like dynamics, I assume due to bio-chemistry&#xA;that is more cyclical and maybe caused by strong stimuli in the first place&#xA;(interestingly I got some of that observed by myself)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There should be more for sure but I like the interesting ones and I got this idea that&#xA;some signal demoralization (non-consuciously like most of things surely)&#xA;as some kind of warfare against mirror-neurones of others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamlet</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:31:24 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamlet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched Hamlet by Zefirelli.&#xA;Not in one session on one hand.&#xA;But on the other hand the second session was&#xA;something different and very fresh for me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alot of times the picture just looks well.&#xA;I definetly need to get to the bottom of it why.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In school I didn&amp;rsquo;t read stuff.&#xA;They forced stuff on us and it didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me.&#xA;After the movie and looking how strangely the story goes I thought about reconsidering that.&#xA;Altohugh of course considering how the exerience is made overall &amp;ndash; not sure if my imagination is going to construct it better from paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
