<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the Face</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a breaking of the fourth wall element in theater/cinema.&#xA;I recall the name only after I start to see significance of such tools.&#xA;For example, in Killer&amp;rsquo;s of the Flower Moon, there are at least two sneaky breakings of the fourth wall&#xA;and one obvious one at the end.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d say, even if sneaky, they signify key moments to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For whatever questionable reason, I watched Perfect Days by Wim Wenders too recently.&#xA;Somehow, the director, even if the he has great work, tends to be mentioned by Russian speaking people who signal sophistication.&#xA;And I&amp;rsquo;m fine if somebody references, at least after watching it, if the reference is good.&#xA;But in that case, the referencer probably asked chat-gpt and got hallucinated and confused mix of stuff.&#xA;So it was the worst possible reference, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to think about that.&#xA;(BTW: I use chat-gpt to put commas around; hopefully, that does not make my references bad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Book</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-read-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 14:21:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/how-to-read-a-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;then&#34;&gt;Then&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I try to install a habit for reading from time to time.&#xA;Previous attempt was Faust that weights 2 kilos because of big format and stylistically different but exceptional pictures on every other page.&#xA;Such pictures were competing with images in the text but I enjoyed both.&#xA;One notable experience such book can give is when you are trying to analyze through some text&#xA;and turn the page and see some unexpected picture.&#xA;Then this picture can sink your active attention as some exit that you grasp and appreciate like you would not expect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
