<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aster on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/aster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aster on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:39:04 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/aster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hereditary (rewatch)</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hereditary_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:39:04 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hereditary_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here when it gets closer to winter small birds come around and periodically knock into windows.&#xA;They can even destroy mosquito nets if humans refuse to feed them.&#xA;As I recall farmers started feeding the population so they clean the trees but now part of the contract between the species is that humans feed them during the winter.&#xA;So while meeting the obligation and observing birds I got some ideas and decided to rewatch Hereditary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hereditary</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hereditary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 18:28:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hereditary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impression&#34;&gt;Impression&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has another level gaslighting with catchlights.&#xA;Also birch trees are my favorite.&#xA;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s hypnotic yet plain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike Midsommar, this one is not funny.&#xA;Yet there is still the sacrifice aspect, but the negative perspective.&#xA;I assume it&amp;rsquo;s The Wicker Man one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also alignable to the unnamed here movie.&#xA;One interesting difference I noticed on the current/first watch is that there is a lack of a defined sense of smell.&#xA;This invisible lead can be connected to different things, but generally speaking I&amp;rsquo;d say Midsommar answers that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Midsommar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/midsommar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 13:19:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/midsommar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first&#34;&gt;First&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If traumatic comedy is a genre then this picture is in it.&#xA;The combination is quite potent and this movie runs with it in both very natural and artistically developed setting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In part the movie is like a trip, but only to the needed extent.&#xA;So it is focused and not vague.&#xA;After the trip, one gets to wind down, and the picture touches some strings too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Talking about the setting, I got to think about ritual and sacrafice.&#xA;These things have changed their form, where they are not lost.&#xA;The picture reminds about the raw and original form and value of these behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
