<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dentist on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/dentist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dentist on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:27:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/dentist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Names</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/three-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:27:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/three-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another trip to a dentist. Nearby dentist this time.&#xA;Initially for this appointment I had to write own name at the website.&#xA;The problem is I feel like I have three of them now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;one is official name transliteration into English; that begs the question of how to pronounce that&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;next is the English version of the name; but I&amp;rsquo;m not from England or the US&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serbian version of the similar name; which should sound most naturally&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So for the appointment I used the Serbian to have less confusion.&#xA;But then already there I used English for communication so I got to think about the naming again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Holes</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/three-holes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 14:31:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/three-holes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan to have a series of posts on my dentist experiences initially.&#xA;But the times are strange already and fashion is ever changing&#xA;so maybe this is going to be the new thing one day.&#xA;In fact I&amp;rsquo;ll be the least surprised when celebrities start to post their&#xA;selfies from dentist chairs with mouths open wide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So after not seeing dentists for some time that was justified by different uncertainty&#xA;I finally went to one and he told me that I can have three holes fixed in one session if I want to.&#xA;And I told him that I&amp;rsquo;m entertaining this idea.&#xA;But the real idea was, whether I should have them done without anesthesia.&#xA;On one hand it is not what I&amp;rsquo;m used to do at all. On the other hand missing&#xA;such an opportunity would be so wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Dentist Experience</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:22:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-time&#34;&gt;This time&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I was about to visit a dentist today.&#xA;It was my last visit in this &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;And I needed to fix a wisdom tooth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And I randomly recollected that at some point in the past when a dentist was injecting anesthesia&#xA;it felt like they are injecting the needle right into the bone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And since this was my last visit I felt like experimentating and not injecting anything this time.&#xA;But I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I will really decide to not use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
