<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stocks on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/stocks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stocks on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:04:15 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/stocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stocks2</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:04:15 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It looks like get levelups and paid-for lessons from the marked every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gotta write my thoughts somewhere so this place seems fit for that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I possibly see what is the difference between a complete &amp;ldquo;hamster&amp;rdquo; and a bit more strategic let&amp;rsquo;s say &amp;ldquo;hunter&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hamster has a very short information window and that makes the thinking impossible so he acts with lizard brain (so looses money).&#xA;Also random tips or even other hamsters &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo; and stuff that is not understandeable as price movement in the moment itself is also not a food for advanced brain so it shrinks its involvement I think and causes what it casuses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stocks</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 07:45:27 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got some cool ride in all directions from SPCE recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I got alot of not-easily to reconcile experience that is not cheep also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway gotta write some my levelup thoughts so I remember them better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unexpected stuff happens at any time and in any combinations. Gotta learn and be ready (chosen strategy) from the decision point.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is about strategy choice from options and then appropriate execution plan and execution and not about any price moves at all&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;margin is a wild thingy, I&amp;rsquo;m not used to that now but gotta improve :) also one should be able to ignore price movements and forget about the account money (and potentially have more cash to compensate for it if negative news coming-out)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;intraday requires back-testing and knowledge of probabilities and stop-loss distance is a crucial part of it&#xA;and actualy automated system I think (so is not really an option outside of some obvious &amp;ldquo;rockets&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;other than intraday holding without margin is easy thing to do but take profits should be automated&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;entry also should be distributed over a period where you want to flatten price movements and completely ignore them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;manipulations or unexpected stuff happens so one cannot be unprepared to anything&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;if you watch at the price charts forget ease and comfort irregardless of where the price goes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is like a work - you need to be on time on crucial points and be ready (also timeboxed decision making, not random urgent stupid actions)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;in a way being serious and methodical works I beleive but also being open-minded for unexpected stuff is a necessary part of it! Because otherwise you are easily manipulated and predicted as the rest of the crowd.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;deciding exit goal and exit points before putting a trade&#xA;and deciding on entry process relaxes you thinking alot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;fresh and not confused brains are a resource - don&amp;rsquo;t overtrade&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;any sign of lack of self-control is a sign of confused brains so access ot investments should be closed at that time!&#xA;(like impulsive buying idea or other indulgent state of mind)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;read books on stuff - they give useful small related advices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t listen to anybody - even if they are right today it is unbeliveably foolish to act on something outside of your understanding&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But don&amp;rsquo;t be disconnected from actual news and don&amp;rsquo;t miss the first hour when they play-out in case you use margin for sure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The best way to use margin is to close it scalp/speculatively I think&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The easiest and profitable thing too is to just make nice bets that have to be automatically fulfilled on money you can forget that exists without use of margin.&#xA;(I still am not good at margin I beleive it can be used in an uptrend to buy corrections, temporaly maybe, but then you can enter some odd-decisions area that I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t want to get experienced at but I feel like I need to get the experience to not have a fear of it. So buying on margin adds complexity for me at this point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;diary or just a sticker card planning of your investment and its outcome and exit points is necessary, also some justification of why it looks like a good investment and why risks can be &amp;ldquo;ignored&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;hamsters loose on any movement of the price either up or down so for them it is best to avoid following it at all&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You always &amp;ldquo;loose&amp;rdquo; somethnig. If not money then opportunities.&#xA;So it is not &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamstering</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 09:25:43 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So here I will write and update on my level-upping as amateur on the market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First in august 2020 probably I got some BA, oil and mostly boring military stocks.&#xA;And I holded them.&#xA;Then I beleive at the president election there was some run that I missed probably.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then there was a vaccine news and I holded for one more day and sold.&#xA;And missed some good actual run from that point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virgin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:31:41 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting stuff with Virgin Galactic stock.&#xA;Alot of people mad and alot of people made money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some theories on what happened:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jeff Who is being salty and is shorting with all the cash&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;stock offering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;profit fixation on the main session&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of hamsters (including me) who missed the tesla hype expected the SPCE to became the new one.&#xA;And I beleive that accounted for bigger than normal swings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
