<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stocks on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/stocks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stocks on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:04:15 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/stocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stocks2</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 12:04:15 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks2/</guid>
      <description>It looks like get levelups and paid-for lessons from the marked every day.&#xA;Gotta write my thoughts somewhere so this place seems fit for that.&#xA;So I possibly see what is the difference between a complete &amp;ldquo;hamster&amp;rdquo; and a bit more strategic let&amp;rsquo;s say &amp;ldquo;hunter&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Hamster has a very short information window and that makes the thinking impossible so he acts with lizard brain (so looses money). Also random tips or even other hamsters &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo; and stuff that is not understandeable as price movement in the moment itself is also not a food for advanced brain so it shrinks its involvement I think and causes what it casuses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stocks</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 07:45:27 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</guid>
      <description>Got some cool ride in all directions from SPCE recently.&#xA;So I got alot of not-easily to reconcile experience that is not cheep also.&#xA;Anyway gotta write some my levelup thoughts so I remember them better.&#xA;Unexpected stuff happens at any time and in any combinations. Gotta learn and be ready (chosen strategy) from the decision point. it is about strategy choice from options and then appropriate execution plan and execution and not about any price moves at all margin is a wild thingy, I&amp;rsquo;m not used to that now but gotta improve :) also one should be able to ignore price movements and forget about the account money (and potentially have more cash to compensate for it if negative news coming-out) intraday requires back-testing and knowledge of probabilities and stop-loss distance is a crucial part of it and actualy automated system I think (so is not really an option outside of some obvious &amp;ldquo;rockets&amp;rdquo;) other than intraday holding without margin is easy thing to do but take profits should be automated entry also should be distributed over a period where you want to flatten price movements and completely ignore them manipulations or unexpected stuff happens so one cannot be unprepared to anything if you watch at the price charts forget ease and comfort irregardless of where the price goes it is like a work - you need to be on time on crucial points and be ready (also timeboxed decision making, not random urgent stupid actions) in a way being serious and methodical works I beleive but also being open-minded for unexpected stuff is a necessary part of it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamstering</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 09:25:43 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</guid>
      <description>So here I will write and update on my level-upping as amateur on the market.&#xA;First in august 2020 probably I got some BA, oil and mostly boring military stocks. And I holded them. Then I beleive at the president election there was some run that I missed probably.&#xA;Then there was a vaccine news and I holded for one more day and sold. And missed some good actual run from that point.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virgin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:31:41 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</guid>
      <description>Interesting stuff with Virgin Galactic stock. Alot of people mad and alot of people made money.&#xA;Some theories on what happened:&#xA;Jeff Who is being salty and is shorting with all the cash stock offering profit fixation on the main session A lot of hamsters (including me) who missed the tesla hype expected the SPCE to became the new one. And I beleive that accounted for bigger than normal swings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
