<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:19:22 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brother Sun, Sister Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:19:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/brother-sun/</guid>
      <description>I watched it some time ago so I may forget someting that I wanted to say here.
It is exalted. I remember that there are some nice images. As a viewer I did beleive that the guy has a vision. And it was compelling in some way to me.
I remembered very obvious scene when the ceremony when hair being cut is followed by sheep flock with some of them being cut too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class War</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:47:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/war/</guid>
      <description>Living in post-soviet union land and having lots of inheritance left and still having big parts of it being relevant I can&amp;rsquo;t be neutral towards the ideology of that time and it&amp;rsquo;s pillars.
One thing that is a pillar AFAIK is the warfare between classes. Modern communists use word oppression for that for example (because fools like words they don&amp;rsquo;t understand).
And I also thought that Marx and all criminal his &amp;ldquo;followers&amp;rdquo; who established that soviet union rule here should be liars and anything they say must be deception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:07:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/gravity/</guid>
      <description>Watched the movie. It seems more balanced than Interstellar. It has both soapy stuff like males self-sacraficing while looking into females face (Interstellar also has exactly that stuff). But it also has more like that will and action against entropy and even gravity itself.
It has some naked legs Lara Croft action too.
It has some of what can be commonly referred as psychological. Initially Lara :) is being handled like a baby in that sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity22</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unity22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 09:02:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unity22/</guid>
      <description>The journey is so inspirational already. There is no doubt that I&amp;rsquo;m going to watch the launch live.
 we are taking impossible and making it inevitable you need the best humans to work on programs like these  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h8T9mVkGh3s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interstellar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:40:35 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/interstellar/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, one day before the historic Unity22 launch I decided to watch Inception. I remembered that the movie was annoying alot of times but stil gave it a try. So this post is about that experience.
Positives I&amp;rsquo;ll start with positives to not be too harsh.
The plot seems to be more interesting that I remembered initially. There were a couple of cool visuals, some nice scenes overall or even I appreciated how certain scenes were directed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamlet</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:31:24 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamlet/</guid>
      <description>Watched Hamlet by Zefirelli. Not in one session on one hand. But on the other hand the second session was something different and very fresh for me.
Alot of times the picture just looks well. I definetly need to get to the bottom of it why.
In school I didn&amp;rsquo;t read stuff. They forced stuff on us and it didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me. After the movie and looking how strangely the story goes I thought about reconsidering that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stocks</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 07:45:27 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stocks/</guid>
      <description>Got some cool ride in all directions from SPCE recently.
So I got alot of not-easily to reconcile experience that is not cheep also.
Anyway gotta write some my levelup thoughts so I remember them better.
 Unexpected stuff happens at any time and in any combinations. Gotta learn and be ready (chosen strategy) from the decision point. it is about strategy choice from options and then appropriate execution plan and execution and not about any price moves at all margin is a wild thingy, I&amp;rsquo;m not used to that now but gotta improve :) also one should be able to ignore price movements and forget about the account money (and potentially have more cash to compensate for it if negative news coming-out) intraday requires back-testing and knowledge of probabilities and stop-loss distance is a crucial part of it and actualy automated system I think (so is not really an option outside of some obvious &amp;ldquo;rockets&amp;rdquo;) other than intraday holding without margin is easy thing to do but take profits should be automated entry also should be distributed over a period where you want to flatten price movements and completely ignore them manipulations or unexpected stuff happens so one cannot be unprepared to anything if you watch at the price charts forget ease and comfort irregardless of where the price goes it is like a work - you need to be on time on crucial points and be ready (also timeboxed decision making, not random urgent stupid actions) in a way being serious and methodical works I beleive but also being open-minded for unexpected stuff is a necessary part of it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamstering</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 09:25:43 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/hamstering/</guid>
      <description>So here I will write and update on my level-upping as amateur on the market.
First in august 2020 probably I got some BA, oil and mostly boring military stocks. And I holded them. Then I beleive at the president election there was some run that I missed probably.
Then there was a vaccine news and I holded for one more day and sold. And missed some good actual run from that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virgin</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 08:31:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/virgin/</guid>
      <description>Interesting stuff with Virgin Galactic stock. Alot of people mad and alot of people made money.
Some theories on what happened:
 Jeff Who is being salty and is shorting with all the cash stock offering profit fixation on the main session  A lot of hamsters (including me) who missed the tesla hype expected the SPCE to became the new one. And I beleive that accounted for bigger than normal swings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea with Mussolini</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 13:21:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tea-mussolini/</guid>
      <description>The movie is like a story with different aspects to it. It has a bit of everything from nice views to light comedy and interesting people in odd situations. But then it turned to be a small puzzle that I got solved here while writing the post.
One thing I got to remember are how imposing Mussolini&amp;rsquo;s table is. Another thing is how nicely and lightly trashy art is being advertised in one scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeffirelli</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zeffirelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:29:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zeffirelli/</guid>
      <description>Here I should have impressions on the works of the director.
Romeo and Juliet I&amp;rsquo;m not going to analyse the content here. Because there has to be more than enough high-quality analysis of Shakespeare.
I liked the main theme. And some scenes for sure. And almost all main characters even if they all act as possessed at different times.
One thing about the movie is that in the process it looks as overly exaggregated and theatrical (as is expected).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/marx-beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:13:54 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/marx-beard/</guid>
      <description>I beleive I found explanation to what caused all the 20th century chaos and ugliness.
One could say it is human nature or nature of existance overall. But I want to get more specific answer.
But even to say that the guy Marx started all the hastle without knowing it is not specific enough. Because one can still zoom-in to find for more fine answer.
I was thinking about it and I think I finally got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form Is More Important</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/form-is-more-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 15:11:26 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/form-is-more-important/</guid>
      <description>I got to beleive that form is more important than the content. Probably because it has to be a reflection of the owner of the content.
So these days I pay attention to form and that affect decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exit Strategy</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/exit-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 15:04:43 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/exit-strategy/</guid>
      <description>I notice that I too often don&amp;rsquo;t have exit strategy. And that single-directedness causes suboptimal behavior.
So actually even if I plan to go and do something. It is useful to have a plan B of how not to do that&amp;hellip;
Sounds odd but this is the case for automoton like me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piano Sight Reading Mini Book</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/piano-sight-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 13:08:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/piano-sight-reading/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Open libraries are so cool. They motivate by themselves. Borrowing and kind-of a limit of time makes the book even more attractive.
Here I just do own notes to review them after I finished reading. It is not something pretending to have been carefully extracted and distilled. Sometimes in the process I just do not record stuff, sometimes I record alot more.
The Book Piano, Guided Sight-Reading. [A New Approach to Piano Study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blowup</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 08:49:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/blowup/</guid>
      <description>My first movie of the director. I have seen some time ago and now decided to give a try to works of Antonioni overall. I put there thoughts I got from it.
Scenes: In the beginning credits are shown in an interesting way you kind of see somethnig by through letters but you only see the gist. The movie starts with fun-car, and then death-camp-looking corridor - contrast from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devolution</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/devolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:36:08 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/devolution/</guid>
      <description>It is strange that in the top politics (the US) we see every next round hitting newst lows compared to previous rounds.
Normally in the nature even insects and bacteria evolve. Why politicians it seems devolve?
I mean if the &amp;ldquo;IQ-descent&amp;rdquo; theory is right then it should make sense. Then it would be cool to see nature restoring evolution back. So that all the good political-stuff is not in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dhammapada 206</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/dhp-206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 15:36:08 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/dhp-206/</guid>
      <description> It is good to see the Noble Ones; to live with them is always a pleasure; not seeing fools is also always a pleasure.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L Innocente</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 19:37:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/l-innocente/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t use names here because they does not matter. It is not a movie for rewatching for me. I feel that that &amp;ldquo;dark freedom&amp;rdquo; mixed with good looks is a bit repulsive. One the other hand it still takes it&amp;rsquo;s own place. With it&amp;rsquo;s own confused ugliness in a nice shaped environment. But still roles do not deserve names from my point of view. No idea why.
TLDR: Crazy miscommunication between genders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senso</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 08:52:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/senso/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful aesthetics. Not to say about views of Venice and Italy. Both strong feelings and something different also.
My version of the movie was missing Livia money explanation scene :). The actress plays very well if you ask me. But she convincingly plays something very different. So I can not imagine that scene and would like to see that!
There is a class difference that I see in different movies. Also there is blindness that is imposed on Livia by her nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shorts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 17:58:46 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shorts/</guid>
      <description>There are alot of fools&amp;hellip; More than they think there are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sect of Blindness</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sect-of-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 15:17:44 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sect-of-blindness/</guid>
      <description>I heave read about some strange practices that some marginal groups or individuals praticed. So there was something like trying to force oneself into seeing non-existing things and not seeing things that are there.
It looks like these days there are adpets at every corner. And they have acheived highest levels of trance.
I assume levels of subversion with the advent of mass media are so high. That they don&amp;rsquo;t need to pratice anything to get that state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Summer</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 09:58:54 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-summer/</guid>
      <description>I found that I pay attention to the good quality views around me more. Summer of course.
There is another thing possibly due to how my memory works. It looks like it is the first time I pay this much attention.
And I think this is the case in many cases.
Like horison line with trees looks so much better. Even colors of leafs and sky there.
Overall blossoming of course is so plentiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lo Straniero / The Stranger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 14:50:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/lo-straniero/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: I have found out that it is by a novel by Camus so I bet this stuff is already analysed well. But I write my thoughts on the movie for myself partially to remember it better and partially to analyze it better in the process of writing/watching. Also writing stuff is not a bad idea by itself.
 Due to me confusing this movie with another I considered comments on the internet odd so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t excited to start watching it and delayed this movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 20:28:00 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/arts/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer I&amp;rsquo;m totally amateur in all this stuff so this &amp;ldquo;early&amp;rdquo; perception/expectation may be defferent from what it is for people who know for sure.
Music Music was one of liberal arts education subjects. I strongly feel that it is for a reason.
On one hand music is a new space to explore so like every new space it offers certain hope and positive expectations.
On the other hand I think the gap between visual and audial is not as big as it seems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ossessione</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 20:20:15 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/ossessione/</guid>
      <description>Watched Obsession by Visconti. I did it in two sessions and the movie is divided in two parts by itself also.
Spoilers ahead of course. I write stuf in two sessions so I may forgot something.
Lightning I like that at the time movies were made with lightning being used at the maximal capacity. You see it being used remarkably through the movie (from mine beginner-enthusiast point of view).
There are different small scenes that I noticed visually even if I don&amp;rsquo;t remember dialogs: only the theme or direction plus some visual clues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandra | Vaghe stelle dell&#39;Orsa</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 18:27:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/orsa/</guid>
      <description>Context I decided to return to quality movies after having a break from wathing anything. And not having time organized resulted in me watching the movie in multiple sessins.
Thoughts It was always visually interesting experience for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect black and white movies being such rich medium. Also all scenes with piano being played on camera I watched twice for sure.
I beleive there is a rewatch value of the movie overall even though it is not that complex in the story as I see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negatives</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/negatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 08:39:44 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/negatives/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have any training or skill in writing but I like ceratin aspects of it and sometimes try to explore there.
The idea is to have a list where I can gradually put my accidental &amp;ldquo;images&amp;rdquo; that I like for some reason. I assume they can be &amp;ldquo;mine&amp;rdquo; but I&amp;rsquo;m not that sure in my memory to be certain.
If they are in negative shades and obviously exagregated they should not feel too bad or emotionally costly I think because that is not the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Fools</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/abstract-fools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 11:05:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/abstract-fools/</guid>
      <description>April fools day is approaching. But looking at trends this is going to be a century of fools anyway.
I thought about abstract notions like freedom, equality, security, even dignity that Visconti recently have impressed on me.
I beleive these notions if allowed to be regarded as meaningful without having them clearly defined create a bad habbit of not using reason at all and leave back doors to humans brains for more cunning ones to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sputnik</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sputnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 15:38:47 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/sputnik/</guid>
      <description>correction: it is not a chimps virus but I find that idea too entertaining still
So I got a shot of the vaccine Sputnik-V (I hope :).
Anyway I got a fever now as normal reaction. Basically I got a modified chimpanzee virus inside which is fun aspect of it.
Another interesting aspect is that I got it at the same day (I hope :) as the first citizen of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visconti</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 14:06:32 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/visconti/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching different Visconti movies these days for the first time.
I decided to have some stuff written. Possibly not very important one but I feel like writing stuff can have some value by itself. Maybe because the writing itself can help me to think and produce some analysis now or even if I will want to add something later.
Also I can&amp;rsquo;t be certain if I keep this with or without spoilers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Rights</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/fish-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 08:06:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/fish-rights/</guid>
      <description>Fishes moving in a flock.
Since humans are more advanced than fish I assume they are even better at such movements and maneuvers. They have more options to do that and have cool creative explanations for doing that.
My favorite flock in political waters are certain kind of individualists. Those who are all very unique of course but also equal for sure.
I bet those owning social networks hide alot of information about such flocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death in Venice</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:06:53 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/death-in-venice/</guid>
      <description>Analysis Meta Being watching Visconti for the first time recently.
Decided to record a post on this one because it is more than it seems in many ways.
I plan to have this one without spoilers because I like myself to find things in movies and there is no value in being explicit potentially ruining that for somebody.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the book. I have checked some comments on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee for love</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 13:49:10 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/coffee/</guid>
      <description>I have got to drinking only water couple of months ago. Before that I was a green-tea addict (only Flying Dragon).
And lately there I got into a nice mix of starting 6-minute productivity diary, meditating, cutting obvious carbs, and listening to a nice episode of elated podcast episode about fighting demons and love for every being. And also to compensate a bit for carbs for starters I got to drink some diet soda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stelling&#43;</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 09:46:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stelling/</guid>
      <description>Non-Stelling First I watched The Godfather, a couple of Nolan movies, Coffee and Cigarettes.
Concerning The Godfather I also watched a comentary and analysis which also adds weight and value to the understanding of how the movie made.
Concerning Nolan. I first thought that he is getting old with his Tenet having stamps and otherwise annoying scenes. Even though I liked ideas and realization and the key scenes of course are my kind of content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bats flu</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stamm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 14:03:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/stamm/</guid>
      <description>I like how these days humanity have developed many strains of the new flu:
 british south african nigerian I beleive there was an italian one also  I like how there is no chinese strain yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zombie Watch</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zombie-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:37:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/zombie-watch/</guid>
      <description>Got to have a glimpse of what russian socio-patriotical channel &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;zvezda&amp;rdquo; shows on sunday mornings.
 first there was an episode about how many more people will have cancer in the future then they had one with staged excerpts related to people being executed by firing squads and how scout who was around this went into the mental house then they got to international politics and what prospects should be there for the state  I do not do hatewatch normally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archeology</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/archeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 20:02:09 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/archeology/</guid>
      <description>It is in a way like in that movie: Inception. There are forgotten situations that has power over you. And there are symbols that you get to have around instead. At some point you decode the symbols back.
It feels energetic but calming. It is too rare an experience to not record it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2020</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 17:57:52 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/march-2020/</guid>
      <description>General I started some new healthy behaviors but otherwise there was no acceleration compared to the previous month.
Reading  I have finished small german language book that was laying around for too long I have started learning a new programming language so I have read a couple of books on it There are more books on it waiting for their turn  Code  I started playing with a physical engine I started playing with NNs Then I lost interest but I&amp;rsquo;m going to return this weekend because there are other motivating factors  What didn&amp;rsquo;t Work Sun Tzu realy wasn&amp;rsquo;t right for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2020</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 09:50:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/february-2020/</guid>
      <description>Reading Concerning reading/audio I have finished Orthodoxy. I wanted to write about it but it is not the case that I am 100% sure about my own view on these topics. Anyway there is a lot of good stuff in the book overall.
Basically the author likes his choice/experience and consistency is not the only value he needs. Although in public policy I would be aganist things like that. Even though author mildly argues for that also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2020</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/january-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 18:36:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/january-2020/</guid>
      <description>I almost stopped reading stuff so I didn&amp;rsquo;t write about anything interesting.
Although I have started listening to Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Orthodoxy and I have given couple of small attempts to continue/restart reading Droyzen and Livy. I&amp;rsquo;m not doing it methodically and I&amp;rsquo;m not really in control of personal time now.
So I decided to write about what I have in mind to address that.
First there is an app idea that I develop when I feel like and then I move to something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Werk Ohne Autor</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/werk-ohne-autor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 12:46:28 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/werk-ohne-autor/</guid>
      <description>I think this post spoils the movie in a way. It can provide different experience to somebody else.
 I have watched the movie. Although art is not somethig I know much, I have a couple of thoughts about art after the movie.
It is about making a name So the stuff modernists produce by just exploring the medium before others done it is worth as much as random numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 20:40:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; Hear me today discoursing in the house of Quadratus.
&amp;ndash; Why should I hear you? Do you wish to show me that you put words together cleverly? You put them together man. And what good will it do you?
 So I have finished listening to an audiobook of teachings of Epictetus. The audiobook is performed by Hayward Morse.
The content is both very sober, straightforward and logical as it is also entertaining and with a lot of humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 18:00:19 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/jordan-peterson/</guid>
      <description>I knew about the guy previously but I was avoiding getting into his stuff at all. But this time I decided to look into his content.
First I got into some debate youtube videos of him. And it was ok.
So I decided to look into his audiobook.
I found the first part quite informative for me:
 I really like biological facts about how things work Christianity as a big sacrafice was new information for me I also enjoyed different literary excerpts (Dostoevsky and others)  But then after 50% the real fun starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective Lies</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 15:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/collective-lies/</guid>
      <description>While reading Marxism by T. Sowell I cought myself on thoughts that the stuff is not as ugly as what is claimed to be applications of it. The stuff even felt attractive in theory.
So I quickly visited one site to see what ideas are there these days.
What I found is some pool of mud filled with red-herrings and repeated talking points. It didn&amp;rsquo;t look that the writers are entirely dumb but that they are a bit psychotic and very ideological and partisan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D and D</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 20:04:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/d-and-d/</guid>
      <description>I have a couple of things that I noticed while reading &amp;ldquo;Discrimination and Disparities&amp;rdquo; by T. Sowell.
Obviously the authour is a very logical and factual no BS guy.
The book is full of tricks politicans use and facts they tend to hide.
I noticed this disambiguation of the term &amp;ldquo;discrimination&amp;rdquo; by the author:
 evidence based discrimination (1A): based on knowledge of traits and behavior of a given individual evidence based discrimination (1B): based on statistics on group behavior, traits arbitrary discrimination (2): arbitrary/irrational  This is how I understood this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tar Pit</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 14:27:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/tar-pit/</guid>
      <description>I decided to write short summary and some ideas after reading &amp;ldquo;Out of the Tar Pit&amp;rdquo;.
Summary It looks like a theoretical high level paper about comlexity in large codebases.
The main point can be statend in the form: eliminate stuff/separate certain parts of the system to reduce power/ability to introduce accedintal complexity.
What is being separated: essential state, essential logic, control.
Also proposed ways to implement these parts:
 state - relaitons logic - pure functions  My Thoughts I am pretty convinced that relations are the way to go for the essential state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das Right</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 09:39:49 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/das-right/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; is the most prominent example of language abuse for politics sake.
 It is short and not some yet another pseudo scientific &amp;ldquo;-ism&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;-fobia&amp;rdquo;. So it looks more natural on the outset; It has &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; in it :) You can create new &amp;ldquo;rights&amp;rdquo; every day by adding different perfixes; You can use it to extract something from somebody; Since it is vague term it can have broad uses especially when it comes to general public; It also informs users on how to act/behave when demanding something from others: righteously;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Code Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 17:31:40 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-code-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>So I decided to put some thoughts about my coding here. There are three of them.
Copy-pasting This is one of my time wasters. I have this expectation that copy-pasted block should just work. But then there are little details that I miss that require a debugging session later.
Copy pasting by itself is not that evil. It can be avoided by additional abstractions. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit to any random abstraction either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Till You Make It</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:46:25 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/till-you-make-it/</guid>
      <description>Today I noticed that I feel unusually proud of myself. I thought that there has to be a reason for that. And indeed I found couple of them.
Then I thought that feeling of pride is not really concious in it&amp;rsquo;s source.
And then I thought about artificial sources.
Given say body positivity. When say fat people are told to feel or pretend to be proud of themselves. This is ambiguous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Dentist Experience</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 12:22:22 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/random-dentist-experience/</guid>
      <description>This time So I was about to visit a dentist today. It was my last visit in this &amp;ldquo;session&amp;rdquo;. And I needed to fix a wisdom tooth.
And I randomly recollected that at some point in the past when a dentist was injecting anestesia it felt like they are injecting the needle right into the bone.
And since this was my last visit I felt like experimentating and not injecting anything this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caesar</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 12:28:45 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/caesar/</guid>
      <description>I really like reading History of Gallic Wars by Caesar.
There are interesting small details everywhere: details about politics, contracts, warfare, decision making.
The narrative itself is also quite fascinating to me.
Also national differences that are depicted in the book are quite entertaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitement</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 12:56:20 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/excitement/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting insight from reading GTD is that there is a level of positive feelings you get from envisioning future results of your projects.
The level tends to go up with the clarity created by use of the process. So the need to have &amp;ldquo;artificial sweeteners&amp;rdquo; goes down.
I think that excitement is the only reasonable expectation from your projects with this system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:54:03 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>There are two benefits I have got from starting reading the GTD book.
 The serenity that allows you to be more focused on the things at hands. Previously unstated projects have come up like a surprise.  So there is more clarity just because of these two reasons. And I eliminated some things I previously assumed to be crucial.
BTW I use org-mode to implement it. I am happy with the proccess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Abstractions</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/real-abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 11:41:48 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/real-abstractions/</guid>
      <description>Abstractions are real.
Brains work with them.
And you can&amp;rsquo;t ignore what goes into your brain.
Things you can&amp;rsquo;t ignore are real for you.
Reality of production is reflected in the product.
 Well. That was a tricky way to state that in the ideal world code quality is measured by the quality of abstractions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Self</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/self-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 09:24:41 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/self-self/</guid>
      <description>There is the idea of being in the moment.
And there is also an idea of future self.
I think the real idea is to have both things reconciled into single, repeatable understanding.
Otherwise you act not in your own interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Toys</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 08:09:06 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/intellectual-toys/</guid>
      <description>I want to write an argument that there is a kind of people who like intellectual toys in certain area.
Earlier they found theology to be interesting.
Later such people were playing with philosophies, ideologies like communism.
And now such people may be writing code.
So people who are into religious fundamentalism or communism should definetly try coding.
Unfortunately in code you cannot use verbal tricks or force. But the good part is that you are not subject to the constrains of the real world either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconstrained Code</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unconstrained-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 09:05:18 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unconstrained-code/</guid>
      <description>I was looking at what I am doing wrong with my personal projects recently. And I think that part of the problem is this unconstrained approach.
So there is the propensity in people to be blindly optimistic about something. I found mine to be interfering with the code.
So I gotta learn some good constraints.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try some very directed and formal approach with explicit principles and compromises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constrained Games</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/constrained-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:39:02 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/constrained-games/</guid>
      <description>Constraints in mobile games are everywhere. And they are so explicit.
I have no idea why people voluntary accept constraints. Maybe because there are &amp;ldquo;opportunities&amp;rdquo; available around the constraints.
Somebody has to make a game where number of opportunities is decreacing all the time. To observe the influence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity Order</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/complexity-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 09:47:54 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/complexity-order/</guid>
      <description>The title may be ambiguous/misleading. And chances are the idea is old.
The idea is that you add complexity in the right order. I think this is the real idea behind KISS/YAGNI/etc..
For me the right/wrong here is intuitive. I need to return to it later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditating again</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 10:07:23 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/forgotten-meditation/</guid>
      <description>Background facts I have not practiced consistently. And I consumed alot of content about it at some point and have forgotten most of it.
Thoughts I&amp;rsquo;m getting to know meditation again. With the first breathes you get to observe/experience Tanha directly. Also the alternative &amp;ldquo;object&amp;rdquo; is available. This is something new for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative inventors</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 12:42:04 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/first-politics-post/</guid>
      <description>I hope this blog is not going to be corrupted by politics too much.
One can sign a propaganda plakat. But one cannot sign a word. How unfortunate it is that so much creativity is unattributed.
Enormous progress has been made from the old words to the new ones. Words like &amp;ldquo;free market&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;pro-choice&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ABC rights&amp;rdquo;, etc&amp;hellip; Only true visionaries can see what new words the future holds for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Started this blog</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 14:04:42 +0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The plan is to post some stuff I do. Like what I read for example. With some analysis maybe.
Only the good stuff.
In the end I should get more invested in the stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
