<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scorsese on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/scorsese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scorsese on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 09:05:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/scorsese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mean Streets</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mean-streets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 09:05:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/mean-streets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think the movie is meant to give general impressions, without making too many points.&#xA;This means that somewhat loose characters and plot are just what they are.&#xA;I say characters and interactions are not meaningfully reducible because this is not The Irishman, where you have plenty of time to analyze.&#xA;Mean Streets is a completely different world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I can see it as a comment on the misuse of religion,&#xA;and the obvious character development is: &amp;ldquo;queen getting balls&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;So I see rewatch value now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Irishman</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-irishman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 08:52:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-irishman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The picture offers enough understated entertainment.&#xA;Not that I watched too closely, but on the obvious side are these:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;fish&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;big ears&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Raging Bull clothes hanger and other small references (accidental or not)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;clock from The Shining -&amp;gt; cyan marriage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The picture obviously features some interesting characters.&#xA;Looking deeper into character flaws would be a different genre of content consumption.&#xA;So, I&amp;rsquo;m reluctant to dive into that right now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, it shows alpha and beta dynamics in criminal systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Temptation of Christ</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/last-temptation-of-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 10:36:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/last-temptation-of-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoilers or not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie tries to be on the human side of things, so religious literacy is not required.&#xA;The picture definitely caused dissonance to some religious folk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think there is some sneaky comedy at the end of the picture.&#xA;That spirit girl is looking so sad at him and even almost rolls her eyes.&#xA;I wonder if those who got agitated and aggressive about the movie got any of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cape Fear</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cape-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 13:36:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/cape-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are references and reinterpretations of some tools used in The Shining inside of this picture.&#xA;The most outstanding verbal reference for me was &amp;ldquo;Come out, come out&amp;rdquo;, spoken outside, because the reference is both implicit and strong, so I predicted it a number of seconds before it actually occurs.&#xA;Just thinking about how the director produced that effect makes for some bad-looking depth packed into that scene.&#xA;So medium development context helps in understanding scenes and details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shutter Island</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shutter-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 21:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/shutter-island/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abstractest spoilers warning possible. AK&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;content&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie works with contradiction coming from impossibility of full truth and perfect justice.&#xA;It shows how violence defines what truth is and the dead end of that way if any justice is to be assumed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, protagonist dispenses violence with his version of justice/truth onto captured German soldiers.&#xA;Then he has to violently protect one-self from what he denies to be the truth, imposing this onto others.&#xA;When he himself is captured, and is surely in the corner, the last resort is violence against oneself.&#xA;What mirrors the German officer from his memories, but this time the roles have switched.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raging Bull</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/raging-bull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:05:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/raging-bull/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think there was general context of hearing how this was one of the movies notably influenced by Powell and Pressburger cinema.&#xA;The movie&amp;rsquo;s title sequence by itself confirms that art-cinema aspect being there.&#xA;And actually it confirms the reference, if one wants to see it from that angle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watching it from that perspective ain&amp;rsquo;t satisaction guaranteed kind of entertainment, but it actually gave me some enjoyable parallels.&#xA;And that development and difference compared to the reference tool used is what enriches overall cinema experience by structuring it more.&#xA;Also it gave some of own picture&amp;rsquo;s language that could be missed without that kind of attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made in England: the Films of Powell and Pressburger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As any good film this documentary addresses different audiences&amp;rsquo; interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It could be seen as an overview and an introduction to the cinema of Powel and Pressburger also branded The Archers.&#xA;I like how creative paths of that collaboration and M. Scorsese are interwoven in different ways.&#xA;So, it can be seen as double documentary to some extent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not a documentary in any dull sense because the subject cinema is so creative, expressive and as strong or as subtle as one allows it to be.&#xA;In 2023 BFI called the event celebrating the artists &amp;ldquo;Cinema Unbound&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the Face</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a breaking of the fourth wall element in theater/cinema.&#xA;I recall the name only after I start to see significance of such tools.&#xA;For example, in Killer&amp;rsquo;s of the Flower Moon, there are at least two sneaky breakings of the fourth wall&#xA;and one obvious one at the end.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;d say, even if sneaky, they signify key moments to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For whatever questionable reason, I watched Perfect Days by Wim Wenders too recently.&#xA;Somehow, the director, even if the he has great work, tends to be mentioned by Russian speaking people who signal sophistication.&#xA;And I&amp;rsquo;m fine if somebody references, at least after watching it, if the reference is good.&#xA;But in that case, the referencer probably asked chat-gpt and got hallucinated and confused mix of stuff.&#xA;So it was the worst possible reference, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to think about that.&#xA;(BTW: I use chat-gpt to put commas around; hopefully, that does not make my references bad).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killers of the Flower Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:56:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;before&#34;&gt;Before&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What got my attention to the movie is unexpected change on one channel.&#xA;The channel had comments turned off and occasionally different art was posted there.&#xA;Then there appeared somewhat simplistic yet dissonant review of the movie and comments went turned on.&#xA;I knew that M. Scorsese looks into ethnical differences and criminal characters and groups.&#xA;I think I guessed right at the time what moved the channel&amp;rsquo;s author.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Stories</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 09:16:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;Talking about the first segment here.&#xA;Awesome and controversial piece.&#xA;Watching this only one time is not getting the value.&#xA;And general context of watching should be different too so I&amp;#39;d recommend arbitrary time gap between sessions.&#xA;Also spoilers here may spoil the second watch too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The first segment of New York Stories is by Martin Scorsese.&#xA;I watched the segment twice with some delay and wrote this later still.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blues</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:52:57 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking into Blues and got this series produced by Scorsese.&#xA;I liked Vinyl series so checking this too sounded like a good idea.&#xA;I watch it in the order of my own relevance/preference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The part by Clint Eastwood got me interested from some unexpected angle.&#xA;Most of the time music itself did not attract me.&#xA;And that got me interested even more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly he tried to capture some of that atmosphere so brought those characters to convey it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
