<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scorsese on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/scorsese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scorsese on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/scorsese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the Face</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 13:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/unmasking-the-face/</guid>
      <description>Context There is a breaking of the fourth wall element in theater/cinema. I recall the name only after I start to see significance of such tools. For example, in Killer&amp;rsquo;s of the Flower Moon, there are at least two sneaky breakings of the fourth wall and one obvious one at the end. I&amp;rsquo;d say, even if sneaky, they signify key moments to consider.&#xA;For whatever questionable reason, I watched Perfect Days by Wim Wenders too recently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Killers of the Flower Moon</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 10:56:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/killers-of-the-flower-moon/</guid>
      <description>Before What got my attention to the movie is unexpected change on one channel. The channel had comments turned off and occasionally different art was posted there. Then there appeared somewhat simplistic yet dissonant review of the movie and comments went turned on. I knew that M. Scorsese looks into ethnical differences and criminal characters and groups. I think I guessed right at the time what moved the channel&amp;rsquo;s author.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York Stories</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 09:16:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/new-york-stories/</guid>
      <description>Talking about the first segment here. Awesome and controversial piece. Watching this only one time is not getting the value. And general context of watching should be different too so I&amp;#39;d recommend arbitrary time gap between sessions. Also spoilers here may spoil the second watch too.&#xA;The first segment of New York Stories is by Martin Scorsese. I watched the segment twice with some delay and wrote this later still.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blues</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:52:57 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/the-blues/</guid>
      <description>Looking into Blues and got this series produced by Scorsese. I liked Vinyl series so checking this too sounded like a good idea. I watch it in the order of my own relevance/preference.&#xA;The part by Clint Eastwood got me interested from some unexpected angle. Most of the time music itself did not attract me. And that got me interested even more.&#xA;Possibly he tried to capture some of that atmosphere so brought those characters to convey it for themselves.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
