<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powell on Let&#39;s see what happens.</title>
    <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/powell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powell on Let&#39;s see what happens.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sowcow.github.io/blog/tags/powell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Made in England: the Films of Powell and Pressburger</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 07:36:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/made-in-england-the-films-of-powell-and-pressburger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As any good film this documentary addresses different audiences&amp;rsquo; interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It could be seen as an overview and an introduction to the cinema of Powel and Pressburger also branded The Archers.&#xA;I like how creative paths of that collaboration and M. Scorsese are interwoven in different ways.&#xA;So, it can be seen as double documentary to some extent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not a documentary in any dull sense because the subject cinema is so creative, expressive and as strong or as subtle as one allows it to be.&#xA;In 2023 BFI called the event celebrating the artists &amp;ldquo;Cinema Unbound&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matter of Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 16:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/matter-of-life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hypnotic start and common but strange finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes things not said or not shown are interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here I see ideas about thunderbolt, neuron growth, ladder, and &amp;ldquo;flight from Berlin&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Also script should have some ideas that did not make it into the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is propaganda angle to it which is fine by me. I think it is still strong even if the idea of Anglo-American cooperation in the new world is ignored.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Narcissus</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:31:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/black-narcissus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a type of lucid Disney movie crossing into a horror film. The earliest erotic movie. Melodrama about nuns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spoilers may lie ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;team&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In director&amp;rsquo;s commentary M. Powell mentions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;high quality of the team and art department&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cases of intrinsic match of actors to roles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;directors role of believing in the project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;how the team kind of lived through the movie (without big picture possibly?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And this final point probably assumes a degree of improvisation on actors part in the process&#xA;and also a degree of freedom during the editing part.&#xA;Although I have information about the director being very exacting.&#xA;So I have no idea really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peeping Tom</title>
      <link>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 15:36:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sowcow.github.io/blog/posts/peeping-tom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert and all that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I watched Peeping Tom a couple of weeks ago.&#xA;It is now or never I should write-down what I thought about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points&#34;&gt;Key points&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;many things at once is how I see it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the idea that fear is the scariest thing is liberating&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;lots of visual language, some just makes you puzzled, some is obvious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it succeeded at confusing me at points surely&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;effect: not scared but puzzled&#xA;(which is good, scaredness would inhibit analysis)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;high contrast movie: hilarious/odd/interesting scenes,&#xA;different personalities,&#xA;direct contrast and directors tools can be seen or&#xA;you just feel their presence even if not sure what exactly is there;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;fearless desensitized vs fearless normal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;magic camera aspect I have not resolved - some positive vision probably&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;topic of desensitization by the industry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;enjoyed accents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality&#34;&gt;Quality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;all this baits you in for partial-rewatch even though&#xA;there is some empuzzlement and repulsion present as a general feeling&#xA;but the director did his work&#xA;by quality in all regards to cover for the theme effect;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the movie is like a shopping stall of goods about directing things&#xA;and producing effects, &amp;ldquo;things perceptable and the general level&#xA;is not distracting your from products&amp;rdquo;,&#xA;so there should be rewatch value from that for sure;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is not at all an ADHD fast-paced salad&#xA;so you have your time to think about stuff,&#xA;I liked that for sure,&#xA;yet it leaves an impresson of being filled with quality material;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;exceprts&#34;&gt;Exceprts&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That &amp;ldquo;he is the director&amp;rdquo; I understood it (but not at that moment)&#xA;as both:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
